[{"id": "1.1", "question": "Which of the following would be defined as real estate as opposed to real property?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Wells, driveways, and signs on a parcel of land."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Mobile homes temporarily parked on a parcel of land."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Timber that has been cut and is lying on a parcel of land."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Business equipment an owner or tenant has placed on a parcel of land."}]}, {"id": "1.2", "question": "Which of the following would be considered a property improvement?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "An alteration to land to make it more useful."}, {"label": "b", "text": "An increase in the value of a property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A chicken coop permanently attached to land."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A parcel of land that has passed a percolation test."}]}, {"id": "1.3", "question": "Which of the following best describes the physical boundaries of land?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The surface of the earth and infinite space above the surface."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The center of the earth and infinite space above the earth."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The surface of the earth and all water and minerals on or below the surface to the center of the\nearth."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The surface of the earth and the air rights above the surface to the point defined by local zoning."}]}, {"id": "1.4", "question": "The \"bundle of rights\" refers to a set of rights", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "enjoyed by the owner of a property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "that is synonymous with the Bill of Rights."}, {"label": "c", "text": "guaranteed to citizens by the Statute of Rights."}, {"label": "d", "text": "specified in a deed or land contract."}]}, {"id": "1.5", "question": "Which of the following best describes the legal concept of personal property?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Any item which is acquired in a fee simple sale transaction."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Any item of property that is not definable as real property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Any movable property owned by an individual, partnership, or corporation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Any item that is not a natural item affixed to the earth."}]}, {"id": "1.6", "question": "The right to encumber a property means that the owner can", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "sell the property to an encumbered party."}, {"label": "b", "text": "pledge the property as collateral for debt."}, {"label": "c", "text": "lease the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "assign the bundle of rights to another."}]}, {"id": "1.7", "question": "A property owner leases 60 acres of agricultural land for a renewable period of 5 years. In the\ncontext of real estate rights, this lease represents a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "transfer of a portion of the bundle of rights."}, {"label": "b", "text": "encroachment on the bundle of rights."}, {"label": "c", "text": "conveyance of the complete bundle of rights."}, {"label": "d", "text": "encumbrance of the tenant\u2019s rights."}]}, {"id": "1.8", "question": "A homeowner is very upset over a drone that a neighbor flies over his house. He takes his case to\ncourt to end this possible violation of rights. Does he have a case, and on what basis?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "No. The neighbor is not physically on his property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "No. The drone is in the air, so he cannot exercise any surface rights."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Yes. The owner has the right to stop encroachments."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Yes. The drones infringe on his air rights."}]}, {"id": "1.9", "question": "Littoral rights apply to which of the following?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Boatable ponds entirely contained within the boundaries of an owner's property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Streams and rivers."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Navigable lakes, seas, and oceans."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Navigable streams and rivers."}]}, {"id": "1.10", "question": "retirees' water rights extend to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the high water mark of the body of water at the shoreline."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the low water mark of the body of water at the shoreline."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the center of the lake."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the end of the pier."}]}, {"id": "1.11", "question": "while living in the home?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "They revert to the state when the property is sold."}, {"label": "b", "text": "They are extinguished."}, {"label": "c", "text": "They are a personal right belonging to an individual owner, not attaching to the real property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "They transfer with the property when the property is sold."}]}, {"id": "1.12", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Lakes."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Seas and oceans."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Streams and rivers."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Navigable lakes."}]}, {"id": "1.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Any item of personal property positioned within the boundaries of a parcel of real estate."}, {"label": "b", "text": "An item of personal property that has been converted to real property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "An item of real property temporarily placed on land for the purpose of conducting a business."}, {"label": "d", "text": "An item of personal property that has been left in one location for a period of six months."}]}, {"id": "1.14", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the owner intended to remove it after a period of time."}, {"label": "b", "text": "it can be removed without altering the appearance of the structure."}, {"label": "c", "text": "it is unnecessary to the physical integrity of the structure."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the owner installed it at some time after acquiring the real property."}]}, {"id": "1.15", "question": "describes what each party owns?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Fifty percent of the physical house and the land it rests on.\nb One hundred percent of the home and the land."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Fifty percent of the estate consisting of the indivisible whole of the real property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Each owns one hundred percent of the estate represented by the real property and fifty percent of\nthe physical house and the land it rests on."}]}, {"id": "1.16", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an estate in land."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a leasehold estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a fee simple estate."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the bundle of rights."}]}, {"id": "1.17", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a public interest."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a police interest."}, {"label": "c", "text": "an encumbrance."}, {"label": "d", "text": "an estate in law."}]}, {"id": "1.18", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a tenancy at sufferance."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a leased fee simple estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a freehold estate."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a leasehold estate."}]}, {"id": "1.19", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "ownership of an interest by a tenant."}, {"label": "b", "text": "temporary ownership of the full bundle of rights in a property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "unlimited ownership of one right in the bundle of rights in a property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "that the estate is limited by a lease term."}]}, {"id": "1.20", "question": "retail purposes. The new owner immediately begins to develop a retail shopping outlet, the grantor\nfinds out and takes the property back. What kind of estate did this landowner convey?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Fee simple absolute."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Life estate with reversion."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Life estate with condition subsequent."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Fee simple defeasible."}]}, {"id": "1.21", "question": "inherit the estate. What kind of estate is it?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "An estate pur autre vie."}, {"label": "b", "text": "An estate for years."}, {"label": "c", "text": "An ordinary life estate."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A legal life estate."}]}, {"id": "1.22", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a conventional life estate."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a legal life estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "an estate created by an owner's agreement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a fee simple absolute."}]}, {"id": "1.23", "question": "new car. The two got married and bought a second home. As a wedding present, Barbara\u2019s father\nbought Louis a motorcycle. Under the law of community property, what property can Louis sell\nwithout his wife\u2019s consent or signature?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The boat and house."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The boat, house, and motorcycle."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The second home and the motorcycle."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The boat and motorcycle."}]}, {"id": "1.24", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The right to exclude everyone from the premises."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The right to encumber the fee interest."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The right to sell the premises."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The right to possess and use the premises."}]}, {"id": "1.25", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the tenant makes, and landlord accepts, regular rent payments."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the term specified in the lease."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the period is less than a year."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the landlord has not sold the property."}]}, {"id": "1.26", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "cannot be terminated."}, {"label": "b", "text": "is terminated only if so stated in the lessee's last will and testament."}, {"label": "c", "text": "terminates on the death of lessor or lessee."}, {"label": "d", "text": "terminates on the date specified in the lease agreement."}]}, {"id": "1.27", "question": "This type of estate is called", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an estate at sufferance."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a holdover estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a canceled leasehold."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a hostile leasehold."}]}, {"id": "1.28", "question": "continues to accept the payments. What kind of leasehold estate exists?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Estate for years."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Estate from period to period."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Estate at will."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Estate at sufferance."}]}, {"id": "1.29", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "tenancy in severalty."}, {"label": "b", "text": "tenancy by the entireties."}, {"label": "c", "text": "absolute fee simple."}, {"label": "d", "text": "legal fee simple."}]}, {"id": "1.30", "question": "owners may sell or transfer his/her interest without consent of the others. This form of ownership is\na", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "joint tenancy."}, {"label": "b", "text": "homestead ownership."}, {"label": "c", "text": "tenancy in common."}, {"label": "d", "text": "estate in severalty."}]}, {"id": "1.31", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Parties must acquire respective interests at the same time."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Parties must be residents of the same state at the time of acquiring the interest."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Parties must be family members."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Parties must have joint financial responsibility."}]}, {"id": "1.32", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "own distinct portions of the physical property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "cannot will their interest to a party outside the tenancy."}, {"label": "c", "text": "may own unequal shares of the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "cannot encumber their interest to outside parties."}]}, {"id": "1.33", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Conventional life estate."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Ordinary life estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Legal life estate."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Community property life estate."}]}, {"id": "1.34", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A homestead interest cannot be conveyed by one spouse."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A homestead interest cannot be passed to the children of the head of household."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A homestead interest is a form of conventional life estate."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A homestead is a primary or secondary residence occupied by a family."}]}, {"id": "1.35", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "sell or transfer his interest without the consent of the other tenants in common."}, {"label": "b", "text": "use his or her interest in the estate to encumber the entire estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "sell, encumber or transfer his or her interest only to the other tenants in common."}, {"label": "d", "text": "sell, encumber or transfer his or her interest only with the consent of all the other tenants in\ncommon."}]}, {"id": "1.36", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Property acquired before marriage"}, {"label": "b", "text": "A motorcycle bought after the marriage with separate property funds"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Income derived from community property"}, {"label": "d", "text": "A mother\u2019s heirloom wedding ring gifted to the wife after her wedding"}]}, {"id": "1.37", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The trustor"}, {"label": "b", "text": "The trustee"}, {"label": "c", "text": "The beneficiary"}, {"label": "d", "text": "The mortgagee"}]}, {"id": "1.38", "question": "During the marriage, John bought a Buick, John and Patricia bought a second property with money\nearned from Patricia's job, and each individual received a motorcycle from Patricia's uncle as a gift.\nWhat property is community property in this marriage?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The SUV, the Buick, and the second property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The SUV, the Buick, the second property, and the motorcycles."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The Buick and the second property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The Buick, the second property, and the motorcycles."}]}, {"id": "1.39", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A cooperative may hold an owner liable for the unpaid operating expenses of other tenants."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The owners have a fee simple interest in the airspace of their respective apartments."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Owners may sublease their apartments even if they sell their stock in the cooperative."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The proprietary lease is guaranteed to have a fixed rate of rent over the life of the lease term."}]}, {"id": "1.40", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The co-owners must be related."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The owners enjoy an indivisible interest."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The tenants must acquire their interests at the same time."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The tenants must pay equal amounts for their interest in the estate."}]}, {"id": "1.41", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "sell her interest to a third party without the consent of Robert."}, {"label": "b", "text": "use her interest in the estate to mortgage the entire estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "sell her interest only to Robert."}, {"label": "d", "text": "sell encumber or transfer her interest only with the consent of Robert."}]}, {"id": "1.42", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It is divided equally among the surviving tenants in common."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The surviving tenants must buy the interest from the deceased tenant's heirs or sell their interests\nto the heirs."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It becomes a joint tenancy."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It passes by probate to the deceased tenant's heirs."}]}, {"id": "1.43", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The tenants can determine the size of the share owned by each tenant."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The size of the tenant's shares is determined by the amount of equity each has invested in the\nproperty."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The tenants have an equal and indivisible ownership interest."}, {"label": "d", "text": "There can be no more than two co-owners, and each has a fifty percent interest."}]}, {"id": "1.44", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "there is a single title to the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "there are as many titles to the property as there are co-owners."}, {"label": "c", "text": "title is held by a trustee."}, {"label": "d", "text": "co-owners who are married hold separate titles."}]}, {"id": "1.45", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the new owner becomes a tenant in common with the other owners, who continue to hold a joint\ntenancy with each other and a tenancy in common with the new owner."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the joint tenancy continues with the new owner as the third joint tenant."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the joint tenancy terminates and all owners become tenants in common."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the joint tenancy terminates and the owners must create a new joint tenancy to include the new\nowner."}]}, {"id": "1.46", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It passes to the decedent's heirs, who become joint tenants."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It passes as a tenancy in common to the decedent's heirs."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The joint tenancy terminates and becomes a tenancy in common with the decedent's heirs and the\nsurviving tenants as co-owners."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It passes to the surviving joint tenants."}]}, {"id": "1.47", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "If they so elect at the time of acquiring title."}, {"label": "b", "text": "If they are blood relatives."}, {"label": "c", "text": "If they are married."}, {"label": "d", "text": "If they incorporate."}]}, {"id": "1.48", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The beneficiary."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The trustor."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The trustee."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The grantor."}]}, {"id": "1.49", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "sell or mortgage the unit without impediment from individual owners of neighboring units."}, {"label": "b", "text": "sell the interest in the physical unit separately from the interest in the common elements."}, {"label": "c", "text": "prevent non-owners from using the unit owner's portion of the common elements."}, {"label": "d", "text": "exclusively possess and use those portions of the common areas structurally or functionally\nnecessary for the operation of the unit."}]}, {"id": "1.50", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the unit's pro rata share of floor space."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the unit's pro rata share of the property value as defined in the declaration."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the number of shares the owner purchased in the condominium association."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the assessed value of the condominium unit."}]}, {"id": "1.51", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "shares in a corporation or association and a proprietary lease in a physical unit."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a fee simple interest in a physical unit plus a tenancy in common in common elements."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a tenancy in common in a physical unit and the common areas."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a ground lease in the physical unit's pro rata share of land and a proprietary lease in the unit."}]}, {"id": "1.52", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the individual unit owners."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the individual unit owners and the cooperative association."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the cooperative developer."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the corporate entity of the cooperative association."}]}, {"id": "1.53", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "undivided interests in the property as tenants in common."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a renewable periodic tenancy from for a portion of a year."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a pro rata share of a leased fee."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a tenancy in severalty for a portion of a year."}]}, {"id": "1.54", "question": "property?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "As soon as it is purchased"}, {"label": "b", "text": "As soon as it is constructed"}, {"label": "c", "text": "As soon as it is affixed to the ground."}, {"label": "d", "text": "This form of property is considered personal property at all times."}]}, {"id": "1.55", "question": "Kiki's annual lease expires on December 31st. On January 7th, Kiki has still not vacated the\npremises. In this case, what happens to this person's tenancy and what is the resulting leasehold\nestate called, if anything?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The tenancy becomes a leasehold by prescription."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The estate becomes a holdover tenancy, a periodic leasehold estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The estate becomes a delinquent estate for years tenancy subject to immediate eviction."}, {"label": "d", "text": "There is no subsequent tenancy; the tenant must vacate immediately.\n\n\n\nTest 2: Encumbrances; Liens; Title Transfer and Recording;\nLeases"}]}, {"id": "2.1", "question": "Which of the following describes an encumbrance?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A third party\u2019s right to encroach upon a property without the permission of the property owner."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A third party\u2019s right to claim the sale proceeds of a property that has been mortgaged as collateral\nfor a loan."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A third party\u2019s interest in a real property that limits the interests of the freehold property owner."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Another's right to acquire a freehold interest in a property against the property owner's wishes."}]}, {"id": "2.2", "question": "Which of the following is true of easements in general?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "They involve the property that contains the easement and a non-owning party."}, {"label": "b", "text": "They apply to a whole property, not to any specific portion of the property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "They only involve the legal owner of the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "They may require a specific use, but cannot prohibit one."}]}, {"id": "2.3", "question": "Mr. King wants to offer 100 acres of his property for sale. Since the property is landlocked, he will\nhave to put in a driveway to the road that will run across his remaining property. What kind of\neasement will he have to grant?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "An easement in gross."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A commercial easement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A personal easement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "An easement appurtenant."}]}, {"id": "2.4", "question": "If property Alpha has a court-ordered easement across property Beta in order for Alpha to have\naccess to a public road, the easement is a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "easement by prescription."}, {"label": "b", "text": "personal easement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "easement by necessity."}, {"label": "d", "text": "easement in gross."}]}, {"id": "2.5", "question": "An encroachment is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an easement that has not been recorded on the title of the burdened property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "an unauthorized physical intrusion of one property into another."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a right granted by a property owner to the owner of an adjoining property to build a structure that\nprotrudes across the property boundary."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a structure that does not comply with a zoning ordinance."}]}, {"id": "2.6", "question": "A court might grant an easement by prescription if", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a town needs to dig a trench across an owner's property to install a sewer line to a neighboring\nproperty, and the owner refuses permission."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a property owner sells the front half of a lot and wants to continue using the driveway to access\nthe rear of the lot."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a trespasser has been using an owner's property for a certain period with the owner's knowledge\nbut without permission."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a property owner wants to prevent the owner of an adjoining property from building a an\nimprovement that blocks her view."}]}, {"id": "2.7", "question": "The purpose of a deed restriction is to enable an owner to specify", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the form of ownership in which a property may be held."}, {"label": "b", "text": "how long a property must be owned before it can be legally transferred."}, {"label": "c", "text": "what groups of people are legally excluded from future ownership of a property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "how a property may be used and what improvements may be built on it."}]}, {"id": "2.8", "question": "Melinda purchases a house and finances it. The lender in turn places a lien on Melinda\u2019s title. The\nlien in this mortgage transaction is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "evidence of debt incurred by a property owner."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a promissory note granted by a property owner as security for a debt."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the creditor's claim against the property as collateral security for the loan."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the document required to clear clouded title."}]}, {"id": "2.9", "question": "In a lien-theory state, what kind of interest does a mortgage lender have in the liened property?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A possessory interest."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A tenancy-by-mortgagee interest."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A legal interest in a pro rata share of the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "An equitable interest."}]}, {"id": "2.10", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Payment of the debt that is the subject of the lien and recording of the satisfaction."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Transfer of the property that has the lien."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Recording of another lien that is superior."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Death of the lienor or lienee."}]}, {"id": "2.11", "question": "debtor's assets, including his real property. This is an example of a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "voluntary junior lien."}, {"label": "b", "text": "involuntary superior lien."}, {"label": "c", "text": "involuntary specific lien."}, {"label": "d", "text": "involuntary general lien."}]}, {"id": "2.12", "question": "against a property. Which lien will be paid first when the property is sold?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Real estate tax lien."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Federal income tax lien."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Judgment lien."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Mortgage lien."}]}, {"id": "2.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "change the date of recording."}, {"label": "b", "text": "lower the amount of the claim."}, {"label": "c", "text": "cancel the lien."}, {"label": "d", "text": "subordinate the lien."}]}, {"id": "2.14", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A court-ordered acceleration of loan payments."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The final step in a bankruptcy filing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A proceeding to enforce a lien by forcing the sale or transfer of a secured property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A proceeding to take equitable title to a property that was liened as security for a mortgage loan."}]}, {"id": "2.15", "question": "lien holder will have to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "file a deficiency suit."}, {"label": "b", "text": "file a foreclosure suit."}, {"label": "c", "text": "file a suit to quiet title."}, {"label": "d", "text": "obtain a quit claim deed."}]}, {"id": "2.16", "question": "title to the liened property directly instead of initiating a court-ordered public sale. This is an\nexample of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "strict foreclosure."}, {"label": "b", "text": "judicial foreclosure."}, {"label": "c", "text": "non-judicial foreclosure."}, {"label": "d", "text": "deed in lieu of foreclosure."}]}, {"id": "2.17", "question": "school bus. One day the property owner dies. What right was Deanna granted originally, and will it\nsurvive the owner\u2019s death?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A personal easement in gross, which continues after the owner's death."}, {"label": "b", "text": "An easement by prescription, which continues after the owner's death."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A license, which continues after the owner's death."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A license, which terminates upon the owner's death."}]}, {"id": "2.18", "question": "belongs to property B. Here, property A is said to be which of the following in relation to property\nB?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Subservient estate."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Servient tenement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Senior tenant."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Dominant tenement."}]}, {"id": "2.19", "question": "accomplish her aim by means of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an injunction."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a deed restriction."}, {"label": "c", "text": "an easement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a land trust."}]}, {"id": "2.20", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It involves a monetary claim against the value of a property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It lowers the value of a property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It is created voluntarily by the property owner."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It attaches to the property rather than to the owner of the property."}]}, {"id": "2.21", "question": "Which of the following defines actual notice?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It is notice published in a newspaper."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It is knowledge one could have or should have obtained."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It is notice explicitly stated in a legal document."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It is knowledge received or imparted through direct experience."}]}, {"id": "2.22", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It is notice published in a newspaper."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It is knowledge one could have or should have obtained."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It is notice explicitly stated in a legal document."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It is knowledge received or imparted through direct experience."}]}, {"id": "2.23", "question": "transferred voluntarily are by", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "grant, deed, and will."}, {"label": "b", "text": "escheat, deed, and covenant."}, {"label": "c", "text": "title certificate, will, and deed."}, {"label": "d", "text": "sale contract, deed, and warrant of seizin."}]}, {"id": "2.24", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It makes the deed valid."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It causes title to pass."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It gives constructive notice of ownership."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It removes all prior recorded encumbrances."}]}, {"id": "2.25", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "habendum clause."}, {"label": "b", "text": "granting clause."}, {"label": "c", "text": "reserving clause."}, {"label": "d", "text": "tenendum clause."}]}, {"id": "2.26", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "general warranty deed."}, {"label": "b", "text": "special warranty deed."}, {"label": "c", "text": "quitclaim deed."}, {"label": "d", "text": "bargain and defend deed."}]}, {"id": "2.27", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "To force the grantor to defend the title against a third party claim."}, {"label": "b", "text": "To terminate a co-ownership estate when one co-owner is unwilling."}, {"label": "c", "text": "To keep the owner's name out of the title records."}, {"label": "d", "text": "To have an encumbrance removed if the lienholder cannot prove its validity."}]}, {"id": "2.28", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A transfer tax based on the price of the property being conveyed."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A tax a title company must pay in order to examine title records in the recorder's office."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A tax collected by attorneys and paid to the state when transfer documents are prepared."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A tax on stamps used to certify the authenticity of a conveyance."}]}, {"id": "2.29", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "testate."}, {"label": "b", "text": "probate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "escheat."}, {"label": "d", "text": "distribution."}]}, {"id": "2.30", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It will escheat to the state or county."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It will transfer to the decedent's executor."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It will be divided equally among adjoining property owners."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It will become a public easement."}]}, {"id": "2.31", "question": "several parcels of privately owned land. What legal power enables the municipality to buy the\nnecessary properties, even against the owners\u2019 wishes?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Estoppel."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Escheat."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Alienation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Eminent domain."}]}, {"id": "2.32", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "openly possessing and claiming the property without the owner's consent."}, {"label": "b", "text": "occupying the property without an occupancy permit."}, {"label": "c", "text": "using the property intermittently and without permission over a period of years."}, {"label": "d", "text": "building a permanent structure on the property."}]}, {"id": "2.33", "question": "Which of the following parties is legally responsible for knowing the condition of the title?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The County Recorder."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The seller's agent."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The buyer."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The mortgage lender."}]}, {"id": "2.34", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a clouded title."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a title plant."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a lien of indeterminate ownership."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a duplicate title."}]}, {"id": "2.35", "question": "from title defects. The kind of policy they bought is a", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "homeowner's insurance policy."}, {"label": "b", "text": "standard owner's title insurance policy."}, {"label": "c", "text": "lender's title insurance policy."}, {"label": "d", "text": "private mortgage insurance policy."}]}, {"id": "2.36", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "voluntary alienation."}, {"label": "b", "text": "involuntary liquidation."}, {"label": "c", "text": "hypothecation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "1031 exchange."}]}, {"id": "2.37", "question": "property\u2019s marketability. This party would most likely use which of the following types of deed?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A sheriff's deed."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A special warranty deed."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A partition deed."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A quitclaim deed."}]}, {"id": "2.38", "question": "If Jennifer has several heirs and dies without a will, the property will", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "pass to the heirs by the laws of descent and distribution."}, {"label": "b", "text": "escheat to the state."}, {"label": "c", "text": "pass to the surviving spouse based on homestead law."}, {"label": "d", "text": "pass to the surviving heirs according to the provisions of the will."}]}, {"id": "2.39", "question": "person makes a claim of ownership to the shack and the land immediately surrounding it that he had\ncleared. This claim will likely be", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "upheld through adverse possession."}, {"label": "b", "text": "upheld because of the length of possession."}, {"label": "c", "text": "declined through the doctrine of prior appropriation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "declined because possession was secretive."}]}, {"id": "2.40", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "insured."}, {"label": "b", "text": "free of undisclosed defects and encumbrances."}, {"label": "c", "text": "abstracted by an attorney."}, {"label": "d", "text": "guaranteed by a title certificate."}]}, {"id": "2.41", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Estate for years."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Estate from period-to-period."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Estate at will."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Estate by the entireties."}]}, {"id": "2.42", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "at any time without notice."}, {"label": "b", "text": "for specified reasonable purposes."}, {"label": "c", "text": "provided the tenant gives prior permission."}, {"label": "d", "text": "only thirty days prior to lease expiration."}]}, {"id": "2.43", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "compliance with the rules and regulations of the building."}, {"label": "b", "text": "payment for any alterations to the leased space."}, {"label": "c", "text": "recording the lease in title records."}, {"label": "d", "text": "occupying the premises throughout the lease term."}]}, {"id": "2.44", "question": "leasehold, this requirement would include", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "insuring the tenant against loss of personal property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "providing required building support and services."}, {"label": "c", "text": "guaranteeing that a fair rent is being charged."}, {"label": "d", "text": "insuring the property for the value of the leasehold."}]}, {"id": "2.45", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the lease automatically terminates."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the tenant's estate has the option of canceling the contract."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the landlord can record a lien against the leased fee interest."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the tenant's estate is still obligated under the lease."}]}, {"id": "2.46", "question": "students move out. Which of the following is true of the remaining rent obligation?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The remaining tenant is responsible for the full rent obligation."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The remaining tenant is responsible for one third of the rent obligation."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The lease is cancelled due to abandonment. Therefore, the rent obligation is extinguished."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The departing tenants have no further rent obligation."}]}, {"id": "2.47", "question": "accomplishes this transfer is a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "deed."}, {"label": "b", "text": "novation."}, {"label": "c", "text": "sublease."}, {"label": "d", "text": "reconveyance"}]}, {"id": "2.48", "question": "operating expenses of the premises such as janitorial and repair expenses. This is an example of a", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "gross lease."}, {"label": "b", "text": "percentage lease."}, {"label": "c", "text": "land lease."}, {"label": "d", "text": "net lease."}]}, {"id": "2.49", "question": "exchange for an additional $5.00 rent per square foot. Another term for this lease is a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "gross lease."}, {"label": "b", "text": "proprietary lease."}, {"label": "c", "text": "exchange lease."}, {"label": "d", "text": "full service net lease."}]}, {"id": "2.50", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A developer wants to acquire a necessary parcel that separates two parcels she already owns."}, {"label": "b", "text": "An owner-developer wants to retain ownership of the land portion of the improved real property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A fast food company wants to place a restaurant in an existing building without buying either\nland or improvement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A farmer wants to sell his property to a mining company."}]}, {"id": "2.51", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "either party giving proper notice."}, {"label": "b", "text": "either party without notice."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a sublease, with the lessor's approval."}, {"label": "d", "text": "an assignment by the lessor."}]}, {"id": "2.52", "question": "date, the lease is regarded as", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "invalid."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a tenancy from period-to-period."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a tenancy at will."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a tenancy for years."}]}, {"id": "2.53", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a hotel."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a single-family residence."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a unit in an apartment building that has fewer than ten units."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a duplex in which the owner occupies one of the units."}]}, {"id": "2.54", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a temporary transfer of legal title."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a limited freehold interest in the air space of her unit."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a temporary possessory interest."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a title conveyance in exchange for rent."}]}, {"id": "2.55", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A freehold estate for years."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A reduced leasehold estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A defeasible estate."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A leased fee estate."}]}, {"id": "2.56", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "transfer the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "encumber the property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "occupy the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "maintain the property."}]}, {"id": "2.57", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The buyer acquires title subject to the lease, which remains in effect."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The lease is cancelled."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The lease expires within thirty days unless renewed."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A new lease is automatically executed."}]}, {"id": "2.58", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Immediately, since it is an invalid lease."}, {"label": "b", "text": "After one year."}, {"label": "c", "text": "When either party gives proper notice."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Whenever the property is sold."}]}, {"id": "2.59", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "leases in excess of one year must be recorded to be enforceable."}, {"label": "b", "text": "oral leases are not enforceable."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a five-year lease must be in writing to be enforceable."}, {"label": "d", "text": "an unwritten lease is fraudulent."}]}, {"id": "2.60", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The subtenant takes over sole responsibility for performance of the original lease contract."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The original tenant retains primary responsibility for performance of the original lease contract."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It does not convey any of the leasehold interest."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It conveys the entire leasehold interest."}]}, {"id": "2.61", "question": "proceeds are insufficient to pay off the loan, and the court orders other property sold to cover the\nshortfall. This action is called a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "strict foreclosure."}, {"label": "b", "text": "suit for specific performance."}, {"label": "c", "text": "equity foreclosure judgment."}, {"label": "d", "text": "deficiency judgment."}]}, {"id": "2.62", "question": "following criteria?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The possession must have been concealed, without permission, and for a statutory period of time."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The possession must have been unconcealed, for the necessary length of time, and without\npermission."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The possession must be with intent, secretive, notorious and hostile."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The possession must be open, without permission, for the statutory period of time, and within the\nnumber of permitted intervals."}]}, {"id": "2.63", "question": "owner actually owns the property. What is another benefit of recording to the homeowner?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Recording instruments establishes the title\u2019s marketability."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Recording the deed prevents any future clouds on title."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Recording prevents lienholders from illegal credit practices."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Recording the deed of conveyance nullifies any and all claims of adverse possession."}]}, {"id": "2.64", "question": "What is one legitimate course of action available to Yvonne?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A vendor's lien"}, {"label": "b", "text": "An intangible lien"}, {"label": "c", "text": "A broker's lien"}, {"label": "d", "text": "A mechanic\u2019s lien"}]}, {"id": "2.65", "question": "close. What is another anomaly of a short sale that makes it a unique conveyance alternative?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The lender must approve of the modified loan and selling terms."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The Real Estate Commission may intervene to protect the broker from seller default."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The broker must take a discount on the conventional commission scale."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The IRS must audit any loan modification.\n\n\n\nTest 3: Land Use; Legal Descriptions; Contract Law"}]}, {"id": "3.1", "question": "Which of the following is true regarding master planning and zoning?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The aggregate of zoning ordinances is the master plan."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A master plan eliminates the need for zoning ordinances."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Master planning is a county-level function; zoning is limited to the city level."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Zoning ordinances are a primary means of keeping land use in harmony with the master plan."}]}, {"id": "3.2", "question": "The basic intent of zoning ordinances is to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "establish the basis for public ownership of land for the common good."}, {"label": "b", "text": "establish subdivision rules and regulations."}, {"label": "c", "text": "specify usage for every parcel within the zoning authority's jurisdiction."}, {"label": "d", "text": "restrict development in unincorporated areas."}]}, {"id": "3.3", "question": "Why do zoning authorities create different types of zones?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "To ensure that a variety of building structures are available in the community."}, {"label": "b", "text": "To separate land uses so that they do not interfere with each other."}, {"label": "c", "text": "To preserve high density land uses."}, {"label": "d", "text": "To discourage industrial and commercial users from relocating."}]}, {"id": "3.4", "question": "The key consideration in granting a zoning exception known as a special exception is which of the\nfollowing?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Hardship"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Change of zones"}, {"label": "c", "text": "The public interest"}, {"label": "d", "text": "The use was legal prior to the new zone creation"}]}, {"id": "3.5", "question": "The intensity of land usage generally refers to what?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The number of residential building lots per acre."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The number of people per square mile."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The number of building permits issued per year within a zoning jurisdiction."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The area of a commercial or industrial facility in relation to the size of the site."}]}, {"id": "3.6", "question": "How does Planned Unit Development zoning vary from ordinary zoning?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It applies only to office parks."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It incorporates a number of different zones within a single property boundary."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It requires that multiple tracts of land be developed according to a single design."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It requires developers to obtain a separate building permit for every structure."}]}, {"id": "3.7", "question": "Which of the following situations is most likely to represent an illegal nonconforming use?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A homeowner in a residential zone converts her residence to a private school."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A homeowner builds a toolshed in a neighborhood where there are no toolsheds."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A storeowner remodels a storefront in accordance with regulations, and then the zoning is\nchanged to residential."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A new zoning ordinance outlaws two-story additions after a homeowner completes an addition."}]}, {"id": "3.8", "question": "What is the difference between a variance and a nonconforming use?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A variance, once granted, is unconditional and permanent."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A variance is granted by the zoning board if the owner has a justifiable reason."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A nonconforming use is allowed if the owner requests it in advance of building."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A nonconforming use violates current zoning, but a variance does not."}]}, {"id": "3.9", "question": "A document certifying that a structure complies with building codes and is ready for use is referred\nto as a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "inspection report."}, {"label": "b", "text": "satisfaction bond."}, {"label": "c", "text": "certificate of occupancy."}, {"label": "d", "text": "user permit."}]}, {"id": "3.10", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It cancels the property owner's mortgage loan balance."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It leaves the property owner with equitable title in place of legal title."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It conveys legal title to the acquiring entity."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It clouds the chain of title by canceling the original grant."}]}, {"id": "3.11", "question": "Reauthorization Act of 1986 provided that", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "large development projects undergo an environmental impact survey immediately after\ncompletion of construction."}, {"label": "b", "text": "industrial users of real estate comply with air quality standards."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the EPA would give financial help to homeowners to remedy any hazardous situation resulting\nfrom radon, asbestos, or lead-based paint."}, {"label": "d", "text": "parties responsible for improper disposal of hazardous waste could be charged for the cleanup\ncosts."}]}, {"id": "3.12", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Individual property rights and the public\u2019s interest."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Public policy makers and community business leaders."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Tenant occupancy specifications and construction contractors."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Individual property owners and municipal planning agencies."}]}, {"id": "3.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "master planning."}, {"label": "b", "text": "preemption."}, {"label": "c", "text": "police power."}, {"label": "d", "text": "concurrency."}]}, {"id": "3.14", "question": "happens?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The owner must pay higher property taxes or give up the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The owner must cede an easement without receiving any compensation."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The municipality annexes the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The owner must sell the property in exchange for market-value compensation."}]}, {"id": "3.15", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "reasonably promote community health, safety and welfare."}, {"label": "b", "text": "comply with federal zoning laws."}, {"label": "c", "text": "apply only to unique properties."}, {"label": "d", "text": "published periodically in the local newspaper."}]}, {"id": "3.16", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "To promote development."}, {"label": "b", "text": "To establish the basis for an inspection."}, {"label": "c", "text": "To promote certificates of occupancy."}, {"label": "d", "text": "To ensure that improvements comply with codes."}]}, {"id": "3.17", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "To increase home values in a neighborhood."}, {"label": "b", "text": "To regulate the density of dwellings in the residential zone."}, {"label": "c", "text": "To prevent families from residing in commercial and industrial sites."}, {"label": "d", "text": "To maximize intensity of usage."}]}, {"id": "3.18", "question": "favorable circumstances, the local authorities may grant permission by allowing", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a special exception."}, {"label": "b", "text": "an illegal nonconforming use."}, {"label": "c", "text": "an easement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a license."}]}, {"id": "3.19", "question": "new ordinances is said to be", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an illegal special exception."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a variance."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a legal nonconforming use."}, {"label": "d", "text": "unmarketable."}]}, {"id": "3.20", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a covenant of restriction."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a plat of subdivision."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a court order."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a developer's pro forma."}]}, {"id": "3.21", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "accurately identifies the boundaries of the property as distinct from all other properties."}, {"label": "b", "text": "accurately describes the location and dimensions of the lot and improvements on the property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "is accepted by a licensed surveyor as suitable for inclusion in a survey of the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "is written by an attorney licensed to practice real estate law in the state in which the property is\nlocated."}]}, {"id": "3.22", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "parallels, base lines, and meridians."}, {"label": "b", "text": "boundaries, distances, and a base line."}, {"label": "c", "text": "reference points, angles, and distances."}, {"label": "d", "text": "lot numbers, sections, and ranges."}]}, {"id": "3.23", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "any row of sections in a township."}, {"label": "b", "text": "two consecutive meridians."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a principal meridian and a base line."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a parallel and a meridian."}]}, {"id": "3.24", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "six consecutive sections of a township."}, {"label": "b", "text": "two consecutive meridians."}, {"label": "c", "text": "two consecutive parallels."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a parallel and a meridian."}]}, {"id": "3.25", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "One mile square."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Six miles by six miles, or 6 miles square."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Thirty-six miles square."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The north and south boundaries are one mile apart; the east and west boundaries are\nindeterminate."}]}, {"id": "3.26", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "1/8."}, {"label": "b", "text": "1/16."}, {"label": "c", "text": "1/32."}, {"label": "d", "text": "1/64."}]}, {"id": "3.27", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "farm properties."}, {"label": "b", "text": "any property in an unincorporated area."}, {"label": "c", "text": "properties where metes and bounds is not acceptable."}, {"label": "d", "text": "properties in a subdivision."}]}, {"id": "3.28", "question": "What kind of description is this?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Plat survey."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Government grid."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Metes and bounds."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Rectangular survey."}]}, {"id": "3.29", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "One."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Six."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Twelve."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Thirty-six."}]}, {"id": "3.30", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "640."}, {"label": "b", "text": "320."}, {"label": "c", "text": "160."}, {"label": "d", "text": "40."}]}, {"id": "3.31", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "money."}, {"label": "b", "text": "something tangible."}, {"label": "c", "text": "something of value traded in exchange for something of value."}, {"label": "d", "text": "something of equal value with whatever is received in exchange."}]}, {"id": "3.32", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "contain a legal description of the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "be written on a form approved by the state bar association."}, {"label": "c", "text": "be acknowledged by three witnesses."}, {"label": "d", "text": "be recorded within three days to be enforceable."}]}, {"id": "3.33", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Forty-eight hours from the time of the offeror's signing of the offer."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Twenty-four hours from the time of the offer's delivery to the seller."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Within 24 hours following the stated expiration."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A reasonable time, or until the expiration date on the offer."}]}, {"id": "3.34", "question": "death, the seller accepts the offer. Which of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The seller can force the buyer's estate to go through with the purchase."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The buyer's death terminated the offer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The seller must make a new offer with the same terms to the buyer's heirs."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The buyer's heirs have the option of enforcing the contract."}]}, {"id": "3.35", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "An exclusive listing agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A personal services agreement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A contract for the sale of undeveloped land."}, {"label": "d", "text": "An employment contract between a broker and a salesperson."}]}, {"id": "3.36", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the parties do not disavow an express contract that has expired."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the parties act is if there is a contract."}, {"label": "c", "text": "an offering party does not receive written notice that the offer has been rejected."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the parties promise to perform their part of the agreement if the other party performs."}]}, {"id": "3.37", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "An expired lease."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A sale contract before closing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A recorded sale contract."}, {"label": "d", "text": "An option to buy after it is exercised."}]}, {"id": "3.38", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "both parties promise to do something in exchange for the other party's performance."}, {"label": "b", "text": "both parties receive equal consideration."}, {"label": "c", "text": "two parties agree to perform a service together."}, {"label": "d", "text": "both parties promise to do something if the other party performs first."}]}, {"id": "3.39", "question": "of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The seller continues to have contractual obligations to the broker."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The contract remains in full force until the expiration date."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The broker may have a claim for marketing expenses expended during the listing term."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The seller cannot sign a listing agreement with another broker."}]}, {"id": "3.40", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a termination of the contract by the mutual consent of the parties."}, {"label": "b", "text": "financial damage suffered by a party because another party has nullified a contract provision."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a lawsuit to force a party to discharge the contract."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the failure of a party to perform according to the terms of the contract."}]}, {"id": "3.41", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The act of withdrawing an offer before it has been accepted."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The act of declaring that a contract is no longer in effect for a given party."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The act of declaring a contract unenforceable."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The act of modifying the terms of an offer."}]}, {"id": "3.42", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "reflect a mutual understanding or agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "use precise wording in a document."}, {"label": "c", "text": "not be executable."}, {"label": "d", "text": "be created only by an attorney."}]}, {"id": "3.43", "question": "with no disqualifying circumstances. Given this situation, it is still possible that the contract may be", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "void."}, {"label": "b", "text": "illegal."}, {"label": "c", "text": "unenforceable."}, {"label": "d", "text": "voidable."}]}, {"id": "3.44", "question": "a trade fixture on behalf of the incompetent party. This contract", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "does not meet validity requirements."}, {"label": "b", "text": "is possibly valid and enforceable."}, {"label": "c", "text": "must be in writing to be valid."}, {"label": "d", "text": "is valid but unenforceable."}]}, {"id": "3.45", "question": "inspection at closing. The seller disagrees, crosses out the provision, then signs and returns the\ndocument to the buyer. At this point, assuming all other contract validity items are in order, the\noriginal offer is now", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an accepted offer, therefore a valid contract."}, {"label": "b", "text": "an executable option."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a counteroffer."}, {"label": "d", "text": "an invalid offer."}]}, {"id": "3.46", "question": "promises to complete construction by November 20. This promise can be construed as", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an option."}, {"label": "b", "text": "mutual consent."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a meeting of the minds."}, {"label": "d", "text": "valuable consideration."}]}, {"id": "3.47", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "is executable."}, {"label": "b", "text": "must be in writing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "is void."}, {"label": "d", "text": "is illegal yet potentially enforceable."}]}, {"id": "3.48", "question": "the contract's provisions", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "must act within a statutory period."}, {"label": "b", "text": "must select a specific, limited course of action for recouping their losses."}, {"label": "c", "text": "must arbitrate prior to taking court action."}, {"label": "d", "text": "must wait a statutory period before they may take legal action."}]}, {"id": "3.49", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "invalidate certain oral contracts."}, {"label": "b", "text": "require certain conveyance-related contracts to be in writing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "nullify oral leases and listing agreements."}, {"label": "d", "text": "eliminate fraud in real estate contracts."}]}, {"id": "3.50", "question": "document to the buyer. Meanwhile, the offer has expired. Which of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The buyer is bound to the contract since it was accepted immediately."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The buyer has no obligations to the seller whatsoever."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The buyer may not rescind the expired offer."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The seller may sue for specific performance."}]}, {"id": "3.51", "question": "characteristic of a deed restriction is that it", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "may be revoked by an owner."}, {"label": "b", "text": "may be exempt from ADA restrictions."}, {"label": "c", "text": "may not be discriminatory."}, {"label": "d", "text": "may not apply to protected classes, vis a vis fair housing laws.\n\n\n\nTest 4: Agency; Listing Agreements"}]}, {"id": "4.1", "question": "The agency relationship is defined by", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the Realtor Code of Ethics."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the laws of agency, or in some states, by statute."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the law of real estate contracts."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the agreement between a principal and an agent."}]}, {"id": "4.2", "question": "Which of the following is true of the connection between compensation and the agency relationship?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "An agreement to give and receive compensation creates an agency relationship."}, {"label": "b", "text": "If an agency relationship exists, the principal must provide valuable consideration to the agent."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The relationship is independent of any compensation arrangement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "If an agency relationship exists, the agent is entitled to compensation."}]}, {"id": "4.3", "question": "One of the parties to an agency relationship defaults, and the agreement terminates. Which of the\nfollowing is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "All obligations are extinguished."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Both parties must continue to perform all other obligations of the agreement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The defaulting party may have a financial consequence."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The damaged party has no claim against the defaulting party."}]}, {"id": "4.4", "question": "Among the fiduciary duties imposed on a real estate agent is the requirement to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "refuse offers the agent knows will be unacceptable to the principal."}, {"label": "b", "text": "present all offers to the principal regardless of their amount."}, {"label": "c", "text": "advise the principal against accepting an offer that is below full price."}, {"label": "d", "text": "advise a prospect that the principal will not accept the prospect's offer in order to elicit a better\noffer."}]}, {"id": "4.5", "question": "One of the agent's fiduciary duties that continues even after a listing agreement expires is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "obedience."}, {"label": "b", "text": "diligence."}, {"label": "c", "text": "confidentiality."}, {"label": "d", "text": "disclosure."}]}, {"id": "4.6", "question": "The standard of care and competence that a principal can expect from an agent is generally that\nwhich is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "specified in the agency agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "necessary to earn the promised compensation."}, {"label": "c", "text": "necessary to procure a customer."}, {"label": "d", "text": "comparable to that of other practitioners in the area."}]}, {"id": "4.7", "question": "Agent Michael is showing his new listing to a buyer who informs him that he has just inherited five\nmillion dollars. Michael is now bound by fiduciary duty to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "keep the information in confidence."}, {"label": "b", "text": "disclose the information to the buyer's agent."}, {"label": "c", "text": "disclose the information to the seller."}, {"label": "d", "text": "verify the buyer's statements before disclosing them to the client."}]}, {"id": "4.8", "question": "Agent Gerry has executed an exclusive buyer broker agreement with the Andersons. The agent\nsubsequently places an offer with Melinda, the exclusive selling agent for the Lincolns, to buy their\nlakefront property. The offer contains provisions for the Lincolns to pay the brokerage commission,\nwhich the Lincolns agree to. Given this set of circumstances, Gerry owes the full set of fiduciary\nduties to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the Andersons."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the Lincolns."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Gerry's broker."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Melinda's broker."}]}, {"id": "4.9", "question": "A subagent is the agent of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the seller."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the buyer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a broker who has an agency relationship with a client."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the client's and the customer's agents."}]}, {"id": "4.10", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Two agents share the exclusive right to represent the same client on all transactions."}, {"label": "b", "text": "One agent represents both sides in a transaction."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A selling agent from one brokerage works with a listing agent from another brokerage to\ncomplete a transaction."}, {"label": "d", "text": "One agent represents two sellers at the same time."}]}, {"id": "4.11", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "preserving the confidentiality of information received from either party."}, {"label": "b", "text": "helping the two parties achieve their respective objectives."}, {"label": "c", "text": "disclosing material facts that affect the value of the property to both parties."}, {"label": "d", "text": "choosing to obey the instructions of one party and informing the other party of the decision."}]}, {"id": "4.12", "question": "relationships?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The agent is showing the client's property to a prospective buyer."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The agent tells an acquaintance at a party about the client's property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The agent answers questions about the client's property for a telephone caller responding to a\nnewspaper ad."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The agent is showing a potential buyer houses in a certain price range in the multiple listing\nbook."}]}, {"id": "4.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "mutual respect, compensation, and confidentiality."}, {"label": "b", "text": "diligence, results, and compensation."}, {"label": "c", "text": "service, marketing, and respect."}, {"label": "d", "text": "good faith, trust and confidence."}]}, {"id": "4.14", "question": "of her business enterprises. The kind of agency she has established is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "limited."}, {"label": "b", "text": "general."}, {"label": "c", "text": "universal."}, {"label": "d", "text": "special."}]}, {"id": "4.15", "question": "represented is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "general."}, {"label": "b", "text": "special."}, {"label": "c", "text": "universal."}, {"label": "d", "text": "no agency."}]}, {"id": "4.16", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an agent accepts an oral listing."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a principal accepts an oral listing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a party creates an agency relationship outside of an express agreement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a principal agrees to all terms of a written listing agreement, whether express or implied."}]}, {"id": "4.17", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Condemnation of the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Mutual consent."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Full performance."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Renewal of the agent's license."}]}, {"id": "4.18", "question": "house is listed and marketed for $530,000. No offers come in, and the listing expires. Three weeks\nlater, the agent confides to a customer that the seller would have sold for less than the listed price.\nWhich of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The agent has violated the duty of confidentiality."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The agent has fulfilled all fiduciary duties, since the listing has expired."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The agent is violating the duties owed this customer."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The agent has created a dual agency situation with the customer."}]}, {"id": "4.19", "question": "campus. The agent refuses to comply. In this case,", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the agent has violated fiduciary duty."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the agent has not violated fiduciary duty."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the agent is liable for breaching the listing terms."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the agent should obey the instruction to salvage the listing."}]}, {"id": "4.20", "question": "on the foundation walls and floor, and informs the agent. The appropriate course of action for the\nagent is to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "immediately contract to paint the ceiling."}, {"label": "b", "text": "immediately contract to repair the roof."}, {"label": "c", "text": "suggest the buyer make a lower-price offer."}, {"label": "d", "text": "inform the seller."}]}, {"id": "4.21", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "prior to completing a listing agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "prior to or upon completion of an offer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "upon the initial contact with the person."}, {"label": "d", "text": "prior to showing properties."}]}, {"id": "4.22", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Immediately prior to the initial contact."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Upon initial contact."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Whenever substantive communication is made beyond casual conversation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Immediately following any offer executed by the customer."}]}, {"id": "4.23", "question": "agent", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "immediately prior to the initial contact."}, {"label": "b", "text": "upon initial contact."}, {"label": "c", "text": "immediately prior to substantive contact."}, {"label": "d", "text": "immediately following any offer executed by the landlord."}]}, {"id": "4.24", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "may not represent one party's interests to the detriment of the other."}, {"label": "b", "text": "must operate without a listing agreement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "must be obedient and loyal to both parties."}, {"label": "d", "text": "must require that the principals refrain from disclosing any material facts to him."}]}, {"id": "4.25", "question": "clause, the agent assures the buyer that the clause does not mean anything significant. If something\ngoes wrong with the transaction, the agent could be liable for", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "violating duties owed a customer."}, {"label": "b", "text": "misinterpreting the clause."}, {"label": "c", "text": "intentional misrepresentation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "practicing law without a license."}]}, {"id": "4.26", "question": "following?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Fiduciary and contractual obligations with the client."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Fiduciary relationships with client and customer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Contractual obligations with cooperating brokers."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Fiduciary obligations with the customer."}]}, {"id": "4.27", "question": "agent to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "create contractual obligations for the client."}, {"label": "b", "text": "negotiate the selling price between client and customer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "hire inspectors, and other individuals to prepare the property for marketing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "market, sell and show the property."}]}, {"id": "4.28", "question": "seller says, \"You can bring me buyers if you want, but I'm not paying you a commission.\" The\nsalesperson then continues to direct buyers to the property. Which of the following is true about this\nsituation?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "There is no agency relationship, and therefore the seller will owe no commission if one of the\nsalesperson's buyers buys the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "An implied agency may have been created, with obligations to perform for both seller and agent."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The seller and agent have an illegal, undisclosed agency relationship."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The agent has an open exclusive agency listing with no commission agreement, and therefore\nowes no fiduciary duties to the seller."}]}, {"id": "4.29", "question": "professionally fulfill the terms of the agreement. To solve the dilemma, the agent assigns the\nagreement to another licensee in the office. Which of the following is true about this situation?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The agent cannot assign the listing agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The new listing agent acquires the full set of fiduciary duties owed to the client."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The new broker has to split any commission that results with the assigning broker."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The original broker has to disclose the assignment to the seller."}]}, {"id": "4.30", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "exclusive agency."}, {"label": "b", "text": "exclusive right to sell."}, {"label": "c", "text": "open listing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "net listing."}]}, {"id": "4.31", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A listing shared by a listing agent and a selling agent."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A listing that a listing agent delegates to a subagent."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A listing that is entered in a multiple listing service to enable cooperation with member brokers."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A listing that authorizes a listing agent to market more than one property for a seller."}]}, {"id": "4.32", "question": "able\u201d in the context of a commissionable transaction?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The customer's offer must be accepted."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The customer must be legally competent to undertake the transaction."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The customer must have a commitment from a lender."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The customer must have no business relationship with the agent."}]}, {"id": "4.33", "question": "delegate the authority to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "obtain and distribute compensation."}, {"label": "b", "text": "provide cooperating brokers with information about the property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "advertise the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "inspect the property for hazardous substances."}]}, {"id": "4.34", "question": "Frank's house. Patrick has a commission agreement with Frank. Who is most likely to be\ncompensated in this scenario?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Peter, since he has a written listing agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Paul, since he is Peter's broker"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Perry, since he found the customer."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Patrick, since he has a commission agreement."}]}, {"id": "4.35", "question": "domain, what is the status of the listing?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The seller's obligations under the listing are assigned to the agency that takes the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It becomes a voidable contract."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The commission clause of the agreement is canceled."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It may be terminated against the agent's will."}]}, {"id": "4.36", "question": "because the seller is too demanding and hot-tempered. What can the seller do in this situation?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Have the licensee\u2019s license revoked for negligence."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Sue the broker for money damages."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Sign a listing agreement with another broker and force the first broker to pay the commission."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Force the broker to perform the contract without compensation."}]}, {"id": "4.37", "question": "This is an example of a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "exclusive right-to sell agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "exclusive agency agreement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "open listing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "net listing."}]}, {"id": "4.38", "question": "procuring cause. This is an example of a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "exclusive right-to rent agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "exclusive agency agreement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "open rental listing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "net lease listing."}]}, {"id": "4.39", "question": "sale price and a net amount, provided the owner receives a minimum amount of proceeds from the\nsale at closing. This is an example of a(n)", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "exclusive right-to sell agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "exclusive agency agreement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "open listing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "net listing."}]}, {"id": "4.40", "question": "buyer representation agreement is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the client."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the commission amount."}, {"label": "c", "text": "fiduciary duties."}, {"label": "d", "text": "regulatory approvals."}]}, {"id": "4.41", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "To list the owner's property in a multiple listing service."}, {"label": "b", "text": "To sell several properties for the owner at once."}, {"label": "c", "text": "To represent both seller and buyer, if necessary, in selling the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "To delegate the listing responsibilities to other agents."}]}, {"id": "4.42", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A broker assign a preferred subagent from other firms to represent each party."}, {"label": "b", "text": "There is no such duty as maintaining confidentiality."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The broker primarily represents the seller."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The broker assigns who is to represent the buyer and seller.\n\n\n\nTest 5: Brokerage Business; Sale Contracts"}]}, {"id": "5.1", "question": "Which of the following business entities is generally prohibited from brokering real estate?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Sole proprietorship."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Partnership."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Corporation for profit."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Non-profit corporation."}]}, {"id": "5.2", "question": "A joint venture may generally broker real estate if the co-venturers", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "form a business trust."}, {"label": "b", "text": "form a co-operative association."}, {"label": "c", "text": "are properly licensed."}, {"label": "d", "text": "are limited partners."}]}, {"id": "5.3", "question": "A licensed salesperson may work only for", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a client who has signed a listing agreement with a licensed broker."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a single employing broker who has an active broker's license."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a client who has signed an authorization agreement with a licensed salesperson."}, {"label": "d", "text": "an employer who has an active or inactive broker's license."}]}, {"id": "5.4", "question": "Which of the following activities is a licensed salesperson allowed to engage in?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Accept a listing that is in an associate\u2019s name."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Accept a commission directly from the MLS."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Offer a property for lease on behalf of the employing broker."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Sign a contract with a management company on behalf of a client."}]}, {"id": "5.5", "question": "If a salesperson has worked on a completed transaction that involved a listing agent, a selling agent,\nand several subagents for each of these, from whom will the salesperson receive any compensation\nthat is due?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The listing agent."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The selling agent."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The seller."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The employing broker."}]}, {"id": "5.6", "question": "A property has sold for $380,000. The listing agreement calls for a commission of 6.5%. The listing\nbroker and selling broker agree to share the commission equally. What will the listing agent receive\nif the agent is scheduled to get a 40% share?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$4,445."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$3,556."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$2,667."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$4,940."}]}, {"id": "5.7", "question": "A real estate salesperson finds a buyer to a For Sale By Owner property. The home sells for\n$245,000, and the seller agrees to pay a commission of 3%. The salesperson is on a 65%\ncommission schedule with her broker, who pays her 65% minus office expenses of $500. How\nmuch will the salesperson receive from this transaction?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$4,778."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$4,452."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$4,278."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$3,175."}]}, {"id": "5.8", "question": "A salesperson makes a listing presentation to a homeseller and obtains a signed listing agreement.\nThe first thing the salesperson must now do is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "make a final pricing determination for the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "negotiate the commission with the client."}, {"label": "c", "text": "complete the signing of the listing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "explain the agency relationship to the client."}]}, {"id": "5.9", "question": "Juan shows a customer a property that is listed by another brokerage firm. He obtains an offer that is\n$15,000 less than the listing price. How should Juan deal with this offer?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Advise the buyer that the offer will be rejected."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Present the offer to the seller at the earliest possible moment."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Ask the listing broker to lower the listing price."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Counter the offer."}]}, {"id": "5.10", "question": "agent as a partial commission advance. What is wrong with this procedure?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Nothing, provided the deposit clears the bank and doesn\u2019t bounce."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The broker and the agent are guilty of price fixing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The broker has illegally converted security funds for business use."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The agent may not be able to return the advance if the transaction falls through."}]}, {"id": "5.11", "question": "identifying the broker?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "When the salesperson is an out-of-state licensee."}, {"label": "b", "text": "When the ad is restricted to the brokerage\u2019s website."}, {"label": "c", "text": "When the advertisement is a silent ad."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Never."}]}, {"id": "5.12", "question": "county. This is a possible violation of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "fair trade and anti-trust laws."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the Statute of Frauds."}, {"label": "c", "text": "contract law."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the Uniform Commercial Code."}]}, {"id": "5.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "An owner agent and a buyer agent combine efforts to complete a sale."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Outside brokers assist a listing agent in procuring a buyer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "An owner or buyer lists with several brokers to complete a transaction."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Agents from a single agency cooperate to generate listings for the broker."}]}, {"id": "5.14", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Any active or inactive broker in the country."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Any duly licensed, active agent or broker."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Any member in good standing in a properly chartered real estate trade organization."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Only members of the National Association of Realtors\u00ae."}]}, {"id": "5.15", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "represent their employing broker in procuring clients and customers."}, {"label": "b", "text": "act directly on a client's behalf to discharge the broker's listing responsibilities."}, {"label": "c", "text": "negotiate and execute contracts for sale on behalf of the client."}, {"label": "d", "text": "take on the listing responsibilities for other listings in MLS."}]}, {"id": "5.16", "question": "licensee?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The IC is responsible for his or her own taxes; the broker does not withhold."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The IC must obtain his or her own training; it is not provided by the broker."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The employee is not entitled to company benefits."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The IC must abide by all office meeting schedules."}]}, {"id": "5.17", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "state regulation."}, {"label": "b", "text": "competitive conditions."}, {"label": "c", "text": "agreement with other brokers in the market."}, {"label": "d", "text": "negotiations with the client."}]}, {"id": "5.18", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "pursue only those offers which are at or near the listed price."}, {"label": "b", "text": "balance the owner's price expectations with the buyer's opinion of value."}, {"label": "c", "text": "avoid disclosing what price the owner will accept."}, {"label": "d", "text": "avoid completing offers that are beneath market value."}]}, {"id": "5.19", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "blending escrow funds on a number of properties in one escrow account."}, {"label": "b", "text": "mixing socially with prospects at open houses or other marketing functions."}, {"label": "c", "text": "allocating commission funds from a transaction for use in the agency's business."}, {"label": "d", "text": "mixing escrow funds with the broker's operating funds."}]}, {"id": "5.20", "question": "Based on this information alone, which of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "There is insufficient evidence of anything other than a normal business practice."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The brokers have engaged in legal collusion."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The brokers have allocated the Phoenix market."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The brokers have illegally fixed prices."}]}, {"id": "5.21", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the completed sale transaction is recorded."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the buyer and seller have agreed to all provisions and have signed the contract."}, {"label": "c", "text": "all the obligations and promises are performed and the transaction is closed."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the loan has been approved, the title insurance has been obtained, and the closing date is set."}]}, {"id": "5.22", "question": "risk of committing an unauthorized practice of law?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Use a standard contract promulgated by a state agency or a real estate board."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Observe ethical standards promulgated by real estate trade organizations."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Offer legal advice only on points of the contract that the agent is absolutely certain about."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Write contract terms that are fair to both buyer and seller."}]}, {"id": "5.23", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "be acknowledged by witnesses."}, {"label": "b", "text": "be written."}, {"label": "c", "text": "be recorded."}, {"label": "d", "text": "have an expiration date."}]}, {"id": "5.24", "question": "salesperson can inform the buyer of the seller\u2019s decision, the buyer delivers a written notice that she\nis opting out and cancelling the agreement. At this point, which of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The contract has been legitimately cancelled and is null and void."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The seller must give the buyer an opportunity to make a new offer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The buyer must perform under the terms of the contract"}, {"label": "d", "text": "The seller must notify the buyer in writing that the buyer is in default."}]}, {"id": "5.25", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A valid blank form that the contract is written on."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A habitable property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "An offer and acceptance."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A marketable title."}]}, {"id": "5.26", "question": "parties?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Legal title."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Lienholder interest."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Reversionary interest."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Equitable title."}]}, {"id": "5.27", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a promise by buyer or seller to perform a specific action."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a condition that, if unmet, renders the contract unenforceable."}, {"label": "c", "text": "one of several alternative actions that buyer or seller may take to satisfy contract requirements."}, {"label": "d", "text": "an optional, unilateral action that either party may take at the request of the other party."}]}, {"id": "5.28", "question": "active termite infestation. On the day of closing, the buyer learns that inspection service did not\nprovide the required written documentation. The buyer then proceeds to declare that the sale is off.\nWhich of the following is true of this situation?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The seller can sue for specific performance."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The buyer will be in default, and liable for damages, if he does not complete the transaction."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The buyer may be able to have the contract canceled."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The contract is automatically void."}]}, {"id": "5.29", "question": "she is buying. After leaving the broker's office, she reconsiders and decides she prefers a different\nproperty. How long does she have to take back her offer?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Until the seller communicates acceptance of the offer."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Until the earnest money deposit check is cashed."}, {"label": "c", "text": "She can take it back at any time, but must forfeit the earnest money."}, {"label": "d", "text": "She cannot take it back until after the expiration date of the offer."}]}, {"id": "5.30", "question": "until 5 p.m. the next day. On Thursday morning, Sally offers Fred $280,000 for the property and\nFred accepts. At 1 p.m. on Thursday afternoon, Jack accepts. Which of the following is true of this\nsituation?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The acceptance by Sally creates a contract and terminates Fred's offer to Jack."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Fred has entered into contracts with both Jack and Sally to sell the same property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Fred's acceptance of Sally's offer is invalidated by Jack's acceptance, because Fred's offer to Jack\nwas made prior to Sally's offer to Fred."}, {"label": "d", "text": "No contract has been created because it is impossible to have two valid sale contracts for the\nsame property."}]}, {"id": "5.31", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "buyer's financial capability."}, {"label": "b", "text": "buyer's source of funds for the down payment."}, {"label": "c", "text": "seller\u2019s acceptable price range."}, {"label": "d", "text": "agency relationships and property condition."}]}, {"id": "5.32", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a promise to sell and a promise to buy."}, {"label": "b", "text": "valuable consideration and a right to buy."}, {"label": "c", "text": "valuable consideration and a promise to buy."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a down payment and a post-dated contract for sale."}]}, {"id": "5.33", "question": "adjoining vacant lot for $10,000 within one year. A few months later, Carboy informs Schmidt that\nshe is ready to exercise her option, but finds that Schmidt has received an offer of $12,000 from\nanother party. Schmidt states that he will accept the offer unless Carboy is willing to match the\n$12,000 offer. Which of the following is true of this situation?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Schmidt must sell to Carboy for $10,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Carboy must pay $12,000 or lose the property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Schmidt may sell to Carboy or the other party, but the price cannot exceed $10,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "If the other party delivers payment before Carboy does, the option is canceled."}]}, {"id": "5.34", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It is assignable only if the contract specifically allows assignment."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It is never assignable."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It is assignable only if the option is exercised."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It is always assignable unless the contract prohibits assignment."}]}, {"id": "5.35", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "At the end of the contract period, the vendee receives equitable title, provided all required\nperiodic payments have been made."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The vendee has no right to possess or occupy the property during the contract period."}, {"label": "c", "text": "At the end of the contract period, the vendor conveys legal title, provided the vendee has fulfilled\nall obligations."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The vendor may cancel the contract at any time before the final payment has been received."}]}, {"id": "5.36", "question": "calls the owner-developer directly on the phone and offers $20,000 over and above the listed price.\nThe developer accepts the offer. At this point,", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the parties have a valid, enforceable sale contract on the home."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the parties have completed a verbal, executory contract."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the parties may not cancel their contract."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the developer could not entertain other offers on the property."}]}, {"id": "5.37", "question": "into financial trouble and assigns the contract to her principal creditor. The buyer cries foul, fearing\nthe property will be lost. Which of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The buyer can sue the assignee to disallow the illegal assignment."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The buyer can take legal action against the assignor."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The assignor has completed a legal action."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The sale contract is nullified."}]}, {"id": "5.38", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the full price of the property is due to the seller at closing."}, {"label": "b", "text": "any loans surviving closing become immediately payable."}, {"label": "c", "text": "all of the seller's debts must be retired before or upon closing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "any conveyance may trigger an acceleration of any loans secured by the property."}]}, {"id": "5.39", "question": "the tenant frantically calls the landlord to exercise the option, offering the apology that she was busy\nwith a death in the family. Which of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Since options contain grace periods, the landlord must sell."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The tenant loses the right to buy, but can claim the money paid for the option from the landlord."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The landlord does not have to sell, but must renew the option."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The option is expired, and the tenant has no rightful claim to money paid for the option."}]}, {"id": "5.40", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "title is conveyed to the buyer, but the seller retains possession for a stipulated time period."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the buyer contracts to pay all cash at closing in exchange for the deed."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the seller retains legal title while the buyer makes partial payments until the contract is fully\nexecuted."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the buyer immediately acquires legal title and takes possession."}]}, {"id": "5.41", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Solicitation Regulation Act."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Telemarketing Prohibition Act."}, {"label": "c", "text": "CAN-SPAM Act."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Telephone Consumer Protection Act"}]}, {"id": "5.42", "question": "discontinue receiving emails from such advertiser. This legislation is called", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the CAN-SPAM Act."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the Truth-in-Advertising Act"}, {"label": "c", "text": "the Telephone Consumer Protection Act"}, {"label": "d", "text": "the Email Advertising Prohibition Act, or EAPA."}]}, {"id": "5.43", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Using operating funds to reimburse a tenant's lease deposit if spent by the broker."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Keeping enough operating funds in a trust account to cover bank fees."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Depositing trust funds in an operating account."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Returning trust funds to a buyer if approved by all parties."}]}, {"id": "5.44", "question": "Nguyen's listings. This would be considered a violation of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "fair trade practices."}, {"label": "b", "text": "redlining."}, {"label": "c", "text": "housing discrimination."}, {"label": "d", "text": "sandbagging.\n\n\n\nTest 6: Economics; Appraisal"}]}, {"id": "6.1", "question": "If the price of an item is increasing, one can usually assume that", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "demand for the item is decreasing in relation to supply of the item."}, {"label": "b", "text": "demand for the item is increasing in relation to supply of the item."}, {"label": "c", "text": "supply of the item is increasing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "demand for the item and supply of the item are increasing."}]}, {"id": "6.2", "question": "When the market for an item has achieved market equilibrium, which of the following statements is\ntrue?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "New suppliers will enter the market and drive the price down."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Demand will slowly taper off, driving the price down."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Unmet demand for the item is directed toward demand for some other item."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Supply and demand are equal, and price and value are equal."}]}, {"id": "6.3", "question": "As an economic product, real estate is distinguished by", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "its homogeneity."}, {"label": "b", "text": "its variety."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the uniqueness of every parcel."}, {"label": "d", "text": "its ability to appreciate in value."}]}, {"id": "6.4", "question": "The city of Stevensville has declared a moratorium on new construction. If demand is increasing,\nwhat will be the likely effect on real estate prices in the area?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Prices level off."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Prices continue to follow the trend that preceded the moratorium."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Prices fall."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Prices rise."}]}, {"id": "6.5", "question": "If Okapi, Inc., a company that markets its sports clothing worldwide, moves into Stevensville and\nhires 100 employees, it is reasonable to expect that the town will experience", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an immediate rise in the demand for industrial real estate, but no other changes in the real estate\nmarket."}, {"label": "b", "text": "an increase in demand for all types of real estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a housing boom, but no other changes in the real estate market."}, {"label": "d", "text": "an immediate increase in the prices for industrial and office real estate, but no impact on the\nresidential market."}]}, {"id": "6.6", "question": "What is \"absorption?\"", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The amount of new space that is added to available space over a period of time."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The number of houses that are built over a period of time."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The amount of space that is occupied at any given time."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The number of available units that become occupied over a period of time."}]}, {"id": "6.7", "question": "When vacancies are declining in a real estate market, it is common for the market to experience", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "rising prices."}, {"label": "b", "text": "falling prices."}, {"label": "c", "text": "falling construction activity."}, {"label": "d", "text": "falling absorption."}]}, {"id": "6.8", "question": "The price for any product is a function of four fundamental determinants of value. These are", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "durability, feasibility, mobility, and location."}, {"label": "b", "text": "desire, utility, scarcity, and purchasing power."}, {"label": "c", "text": "popularity, recognizability, promotion, and rebate."}, {"label": "d", "text": "fungibility, costs, convenience, and uniqueness."}]}, {"id": "6.9", "question": "A town is rapidly growing, but all the buildable vacant lots in the most desirable area have already\nbeen occupied. In this case, it is likely that the price of existing homes in that area", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "will stabilize, since the population must stabilize."}, {"label": "b", "text": "will increase."}, {"label": "c", "text": "will decline, since no further building can take place."}, {"label": "d", "text": "will not show any predictable movement."}]}, {"id": "6.10", "question": "an example of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "supply outstripping demand."}, {"label": "b", "text": "demand outstripping value."}, {"label": "c", "text": "consumer optimism."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the market tending toward equilibrium."}]}, {"id": "6.11", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "demand has outstripped supply of space."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the market is in equilibrium."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the market is over-supplied."}, {"label": "d", "text": "employment is increasing."}]}, {"id": "6.12", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "have been increasing."}, {"label": "b", "text": "have been declining."}, {"label": "c", "text": "have been in equilibrium."}, {"label": "d", "text": "have exceeded supply."}]}, {"id": "6.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Its physical form is fixed."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Real estate is defined as land, not water."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It is often difficult to convert to cash."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It cannot be moved."}]}, {"id": "6.14", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The lowest category of employment in terms of wages and desirability"}, {"label": "b", "text": "The number of persons employed in base industries in an area"}, {"label": "c", "text": "The number of persons employed on military bases in an area"}, {"label": "d", "text": "The labor pool available for employment in all industries in an area"}]}, {"id": "6.15", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A property that has no owner-occupant"}, {"label": "b", "text": "The total number of properties of a certain type that are on the market at a given time"}, {"label": "c", "text": "The absence of certain types of users in a given market area"}, {"label": "d", "text": "The total existing space of a certain type that is unoccupied at a given time"}]}, {"id": "6.16", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "local government influencing the real estate market, regardless of demand."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the natural result of demand exceeding supply in a local market."}, {"label": "c", "text": "government promotion of the free market concept in the local real estate market."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a government policy that aims to restrain a trend of rising prices in the local real estate market."}]}, {"id": "6.17", "question": "local, rather than regional, national, or global?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Changes in money supply"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Federal Reserve interest rates"}, {"label": "c", "text": "In- and out-migrations of major employers"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Trade imbalances with foreign trading partners"}]}, {"id": "6.18", "question": "most likely be the immediate effect on the real estate market?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Demand increases and prices rise."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Vacancy rises and prices fall."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Absorption and vacancy decrease."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Supply decreases relative to demand."}]}, {"id": "6.19", "question": "property amenities, and quality of life in their demand for real estate?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Retail"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Office"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Industrial"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Residential"}]}, {"id": "6.20", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "its easy convertibility to cash."}, {"label": "b", "text": "its quick response to changes in supply-demand balance."}, {"label": "c", "text": "its susceptibility to swings in the local economy."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the easy substitutability of one item for another."}]}, {"id": "6.21", "question": "out at a rate of $2,700 a month. In paying a price based on the property\u2019s ability to generate a\ndesired future income, Parsons was motivated by the economic principle known as", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "substitution."}, {"label": "b", "text": "anticipation."}, {"label": "c", "text": "supply and demand."}, {"label": "d", "text": "utility."}]}, {"id": "6.22", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A homebuyer makes a down payment of 20% instead of the 10% the lender requires."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A homeowner adds a third bathroom to a house and thereby increases the appraised value by\n$10,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The appraised value of a house goes up by $20,000 over a two-year period because of the prices\nrecently paid for other houses in the neighborhood."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Because of a decline in mortgage interest rates, a homeowner in a certain market is able to list her\nhouse at a higher price."}]}, {"id": "6.23", "question": "value than the sum of the values of the two separate properties, the applicable principle of value is\ncalled", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "assemblage."}, {"label": "b", "text": "accretion."}, {"label": "c", "text": "progression."}, {"label": "d", "text": "subdivision."}]}, {"id": "6.24", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "There is no difference."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Market value is a broker\u2019s estimate; market price is a precise number derived by a licensed\nappraiser."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Market value is an average price derived from comparable sales; market price is a price based on\nthe cost of creating the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Market value is an estimate; market price is the price at which a property sold."}]}, {"id": "6.25", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Countable living area must be attached to the main house."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Closets must be excluded from gross living area."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The property must be finished, i.e., have completed studwork and sub-flooring."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Enclosed porches and stairways cannot be counted as living area."}]}, {"id": "6.26", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "From the lot's area, minus the area of improved buildings"}, {"label": "b", "text": "From the exterior walls, above grade, excluding open areas"}, {"label": "c", "text": "By measuring the interior rooms"}, {"label": "d", "text": "By measuring area of all enclosed rooms, minus the basement and attic"}]}, {"id": "6.27", "question": "approach?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Find the median price of recently sold comparable properties and add or subtract dollar amounts\nin the subject property to account for competitive differences."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Make dollar adjustments to the sale prices of comparable properties to account for competitive\ndifferences with the subject."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Find at least three comparable properties that are currently for sale and make dollar adjustments\nto the listing prices to account for competitive differences with the subject."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Apply an appreciation factor to the price at which the subject property most recently sold and\nmake dollar adjustments to account for competitive differences with comparable properties\ncurrently for sale."}]}, {"id": "6.28", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "takes into account the subject property's investment value."}, {"label": "b", "text": "reveals the profit margin of the builder or developer of the subject property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "discovers the underlying value of the subject property apart from the influence of competing\nproperties."}, {"label": "d", "text": "takes into account the competitive value of specific amenities of the subject property."}]}, {"id": "6.29", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "adds value to a comparable that is inferior to the subject property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "adds value to the subject property if it is inferior to a comparable."}, {"label": "c", "text": "subtracts value from a comparable that is inferior to the subject property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "subtracts value from the subject property if it is inferior to a comparable."}]}, {"id": "6.30", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "requires the most and largest adjustments."}, {"label": "b", "text": "requires the fewest and smallest adjustments."}, {"label": "c", "text": "sold most recently at the highest price."}, {"label": "d", "text": "is located closest to the subject property."}]}, {"id": "6.31", "question": "two bathrooms, and a patio. The appraiser selects a comparable house that has three bedrooms, 3\nbathrooms, and no patio. The comparable house just sold for $400,000. A bath is valued at $7,000,\nand a patio at $2,000. Assuming all else is equal, what is the adjusted value of the comparable?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$402,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$407,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$395,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$405,000."}]}, {"id": "6.32", "question": "to appraisal?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Apply a depreciation factor to the reported actual cost of acquiring and improving the subject\nproperty."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Estimate the cost of building the improvements on the subject property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Estimate the land value and add to this the actual cost of the improvements adjusted for\ncompetitive differences with similar properties."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Add the estimated land value and cost of improvements and subtract the accrued depreciation of\nthe improvements."}]}, {"id": "6.33", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "takes into account the amount of money required to develop a similar property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "is very accurate for a property with new improvements that represent the highest and best use."}, {"label": "c", "text": "results in an actual price in dollars instead of an estimated value."}, {"label": "d", "text": "reveals the owner's return on money invested in the cost of development."}]}, {"id": "6.34", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "eventually, a property loses all of its value."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a property loses a portion of its value each year because of economic obsolescence."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a property loses the same increment of value each year over the economic life of the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the value lost to depreciation is incurable."}]}, {"id": "6.35", "question": "$150,000 and the replacement cost of the improvements is $475,000. Total depreciation from all\ncauses is $50,000. What is the indicated value of the property?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$675,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$650,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$625,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$575,000."}]}, {"id": "6.36", "question": "approach to appraisal?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Apply a rate of return to the price paid for an income property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Divide the income a property generates by a rate of return."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Estimate the amount of income a property must generate to return the capital amount invested in\nit."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Estimate the rate of return a property owner receives from income generated by the property."}]}, {"id": "6.37", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "uses a rate of return that is required for all potential purchasers in a market."}, {"label": "b", "text": "yields an accurate projection of investment income."}, {"label": "c", "text": "uses a method that is also used by investors to determine how much they should pay for an\ninvestment property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "can be used with any type of property in any market."}]}, {"id": "6.38", "question": "estimated gross income of $60,000, vacancy and credit losses of $3,000, and operating expenses of\n$20,000. Using a capitalization rate of ten percent, what is the indicated value (to the nearest\n$1,000)?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$370,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$400,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$570,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$600,000."}]}, {"id": "6.39", "question": "monthly gross rent multiplier?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "12.5"}, {"label": "b", "text": ".01."}, {"label": "c", "text": ".08."}, {"label": "d", "text": "150."}]}, {"id": "6.40", "question": "from market data is 14.1. What estimated sale price (to the nearest $1,000) is indicated?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$338,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$204,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$406,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$346,000."}]}, {"id": "6.41", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a licensed real estate school."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the Appraisal Institute."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the state in which the appraiser operates."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the Appraisal Review Board."}]}, {"id": "6.42", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery and Enforcement Act (FIRREA)."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice Act (USPAPA)."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The Appraisal Foundation Authorization and Reform Act (AFAR)."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The Federal Institution for Regulation and Enforcement of Appraisal Act (FIREAA)."}]}, {"id": "6.43", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "if two similar properties are for sale, a buyer will purchase the cheaper of the two."}, {"label": "b", "text": "if one of two adjacent homes is more valuable, the price of the other home will tend to rise."}, {"label": "c", "text": "if too many properties are built in a market, the prices will tend to go down."}, {"label": "d", "text": "people will readily move to another home if it is of equal value."}]}, {"id": "6.44", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "is physically and financially feasible, legal, and the most productive."}, {"label": "b", "text": "is legal, feasible, and deemed the most appropriate by zoning authorities."}, {"label": "c", "text": "entails the largest building that zoning ordinances will allow developers to erect."}, {"label": "d", "text": "conforms to other properties in the area."}]}, {"id": "6.45", "question": "adjoining property owner, Ken, had tried to buy the property for $370,000, but had been refused.\nHe now offers Lynne $380,000 for the house. Lynne is interested, so she hires an appraiser. The\nappraiser returns an estimate of value of $400,000. Which of these numbers can be called the market\nvalue?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$375,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$380,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$390,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$400,000."}]}, {"id": "6.46", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "there may be no recent sale price data in the market."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the approach is not based on the principle of substitution."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the approach is only accurate with unique, special purpose properties."}, {"label": "d", "text": "sale prices cannot be compared, since all real estate is different."}]}, {"id": "6.47", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "chooses nearby comparables, adjusts the subject for differences, and estimates the value."}, {"label": "b", "text": "gathers relevant price data, applies the data to the subject, and estimates the value."}, {"label": "c", "text": "selects comparable properties, adjusts the comparables, and estimates the value."}, {"label": "d", "text": "identifies the price previously paid, applies an appreciation rate, and estimates the value."}]}, {"id": "6.48", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the buyer obtains conventional financing for the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the seller offers below-market seller financing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a comparable is located in another, albeit similar neighborhood."}, {"label": "d", "text": "one property has a hip roof and the other has a gabled roof."}]}, {"id": "6.49", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "averages the comparable values."}, {"label": "b", "text": "weights the comparables."}, {"label": "c", "text": "identifies the subject\u2019s value as that of the middle value of the comparables."}, {"label": "d", "text": "identifies the subject's value as that of the nearest comparable."}]}, {"id": "6.50", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "builders may not pay market value for materials or labor."}, {"label": "b", "text": "market value is not always the same as what the property cost."}, {"label": "c", "text": "comparables used may not have similar quality of construction."}, {"label": "d", "text": "new properties have inestimable costs and rates of depreciation."}]}, {"id": "6.51", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "reproduction cost."}, {"label": "b", "text": "replacement cost."}, {"label": "c", "text": "restitution cost."}, {"label": "d", "text": "reconstruction cost."}]}, {"id": "6.52", "question": "This is an example of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "physical deterioration."}, {"label": "b", "text": "economic obsolescence."}, {"label": "c", "text": "incurable depreciation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "functional obsolescence."}]}, {"id": "6.53", "question": "properties. This is an example of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "curable external obsolescence."}, {"label": "b", "text": "incurable economic obsolescence."}, {"label": "c", "text": "functional obsolescence."}, {"label": "d", "text": "physical deterioration."}]}, {"id": "6.54", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "deterioration."}, {"label": "b", "text": "obsolescence."}, {"label": "c", "text": "depreciation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "deflation."}]}, {"id": "6.55", "question": "appraiser", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "estimates depreciation, subtracts depreciation from cost, and adds back the land value."}, {"label": "b", "text": "subtracts deterioration from cost, estimates land depreciation, and totals the two values."}, {"label": "c", "text": "estimates depreciation of land and improvements and subtracts the total from original cost."}, {"label": "d", "text": "estimates obsolescence and subtracts from the cost of land and improvements."}]}, {"id": "6.56", "question": "and disclosures?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act (FIRREA)"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice (USPAP)"}, {"label": "c", "text": "National Association of Realtors\u00ae\u2019 Code of Ethics"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Federal Appraisal Regulation and Licensing Board.\n\n\n\nTest 7: Finance"}]}, {"id": "7.1", "question": "What is a lien-theory state?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A state in which a mortgagee holds legal title to a secured property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A state in which a mortgagee has equitable title to a secured property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A state that allows a real estate owner's creditors to record liens against the owner's property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A state in which a lien is considered as a conveyance."}]}, {"id": "7.2", "question": "What is the function of a note in a mortgage or trust deed financing arrangement?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It is the lender's security instrument in the collateral property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It is evidence of ownership of the mortgage or trust deed."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It contains the borrower's promise to maintain the value of the property given as collateral for a\nloan."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It is evidence of the borrower's debt to the lender."}]}, {"id": "7.3", "question": "When homebuyer Henry pledges his newly purchased home as collateral for a mortgage loan, the\nevidence of the pledge is the", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "trust deed or mortgage."}, {"label": "b", "text": "promissory note."}, {"label": "c", "text": "loan commitment."}, {"label": "d", "text": "loan receipt."}]}, {"id": "7.4", "question": "The borrower in a mortgage loan transaction is known as the", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "mortgagee."}, {"label": "b", "text": "mortgagor."}, {"label": "c", "text": "lienor."}, {"label": "d", "text": "trustee."}]}, {"id": "7.5", "question": "If a borrower obtains an interest-only loan of $200,000 at an annual interest rate of 6%, what is the\nmonthly interest payment?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,200."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$600."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$500."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$1,000."}]}, {"id": "7.6", "question": "If a borrower's monthly interest payment on an interest-only loan at an annual interest rate of 6% is\n$5,000, how much was the loan amount?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$720,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$1,000,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$1,200,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$500,000."}]}, {"id": "7.7", "question": "A borrower of a $250,000 interest-only loan makes annual interest payments of $18,750. What\ninterest rate is the borrower paying?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "7.5%."}, {"label": "b", "text": ".75%."}, {"label": "c", "text": "3.75%."}, {"label": "d", "text": "8.5%."}]}, {"id": "7.8", "question": "Maria borrows $600,000 and pays two points for the loan. How much does she pay in points?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,200."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$12,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$7,200."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It depends on the interest rate."}]}, {"id": "7.9", "question": "Which of the following is true of an amortizing loan?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The amount of annual interest paid is the same for every year of the loan term."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Part of each periodic payment is applied to repayment of the loan balance in advance and part is\napplied to payment of interest in arrears."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Except for any points that may be paid, the interest on the loan balance is usually paid in advance."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The interest rate is reduced each year to maintain equal payments even though the outstanding\nloan balance is smaller."}]}, {"id": "7.10", "question": "for which the borrower is making a down payment of less than 20%, the lender is likely to require\nthe borrower to obtain", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a subrogation agreement."}, {"label": "b", "text": "private mortgage insurance."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a letter of credit."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a co-signer on the note."}]}, {"id": "7.11", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The percentage of a lender's portfolio that is composed of mortgage loans."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The ratio of borrowed principal plus total interest to the appraised value of the collateral property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The ratio of a lender's return on a mortgage loan to the value of the collateral property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The fraction of the appraised value of the property offered as collateral which the lender is\nwilling to lend."}]}, {"id": "7.12", "question": "will lend on the property is the", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "mortgage insurance coverage amount."}, {"label": "b", "text": "lender's profit margin."}, {"label": "c", "text": "buyer's down payment."}, {"label": "d", "text": "origination fee."}]}, {"id": "7.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "refusing a loan because the borrower does not match the lender\u2019s target market."}, {"label": "b", "text": "including income from self-employment in the borrower's qualifying income."}, {"label": "c", "text": "requiring both spouses to sign the loan application form."}, {"label": "d", "text": "refusing a loan because a borrower has a defective credit report."}]}, {"id": "7.14", "question": "to pay for monthly housing expense to qualify for a loan if the lender uses an income ratio of 28%?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$2,160."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$1,680."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$1,068."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$840."}]}, {"id": "7.15", "question": "borrowed the down payment from an uncle and has to repay that loan. Bob should expect that AMC\nBank will", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "refuse the application."}, {"label": "b", "text": "adjust the applicant's debt ratio calculation and lower the loan amount."}, {"label": "c", "text": "increase the loan amount to enable the borrower to pay off the loan to the relative."}, {"label": "d", "text": "require the borrower to make payments to an escrow account for repayment of the relative's loan."}]}, {"id": "7.16", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "All loans."}, {"label": "b", "text": "All loans secured by real estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "All loans secured by a residence."}, {"label": "d", "text": "All loans over $25,000."}]}, {"id": "7.17", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the lender has the right to change the terms of the loan within a certain period."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the lender has the right to accelerate repayment of the loan because of a change in the borrower's\ncredit status."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the borrower has the right to pay off the loan ahead of schedule with no penalty."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the borrower has a limited right to cancel the transaction within a certain period."}]}, {"id": "7.18", "question": "qualifying a potential buyer, may not", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "tell a rejected loan applicant the reasons for the rejection."}, {"label": "b", "text": "ask the buyer/borrower about his/her religion or national origin."}, {"label": "c", "text": "ask the buyer/borrower to explain unconventional sources of income."}, {"label": "d", "text": "use a credit report that has not been provided to the borrower."}]}, {"id": "7.19", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "backed by the Federal National Mortgage Association."}, {"label": "b", "text": "insured under Section 203(b) of the Federal Housing Administration loan program."}, {"label": "c", "text": "guaranteed by the Government National Mortgage Association."}, {"label": "d", "text": "not FHA-insured or VA-guaranteed."}]}, {"id": "7.20", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "unrestricted."}, {"label": "b", "text": "limited by when the loan was originated."}, {"label": "c", "text": "limited to owner-occupied properties."}, {"label": "d", "text": "prohibited on all existing loans under current regulations."}]}, {"id": "7.21", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "how long an individual served in the military."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the maximum loan amount an approved lender can give to veterans."}, {"label": "c", "text": "how much of a loan the VA will guarantee."}, {"label": "d", "text": "whether a lender is approved to issue VA-guaranteed loans."}]}, {"id": "7.22", "question": "principal balance at the end of the loan term?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$36,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$450,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$4,220."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Zero."}]}, {"id": "7.23", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A bank gives a buyer a senior mortgage loan that fully covers the cost of purchasing the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The buyer gives the seller a mortgage and note as part of the purchase price of the property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A land trust holds title to the property while the buyer makes periodic installment payments to the\nseller."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The seller uses the purchase money obtained from the buyer's mortgage loan to repay the seller's\noutstanding loan balance."}]}, {"id": "7.24", "question": "collateral for the loan. The homeowner retains title to the property. This is an example of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "intermediation."}, {"label": "b", "text": "forfeiture."}, {"label": "c", "text": "hypothecation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "subordination."}]}, {"id": "7.25", "question": "transaction?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The borrower gives the lender a note and a mortgage in exchange for loan funds."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The lender gives the borrower a mortgage and receives a note in exchange for loan funds."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The borrower receives a note in exchange for a mortgage from the lender."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The lender gives the borrower a note, loan funds and a mortgage."}]}, {"id": "7.26", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The beneficiary conveys title to a trustee in exchange for loan funds."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The trustee conveys title to a beneficiary in exchange for loan funds."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The trustor conveys title to a trustee in exchange for loan funds from the beneficiary."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The trustee conveys title to a trustor in exchange for loan funds from the beneficiary."}]}, {"id": "7.27", "question": "payoff period. They are in a", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "title-theory state."}, {"label": "b", "text": "lien-theory state."}, {"label": "c", "text": "state allowing land trusts."}, {"label": "d", "text": "state where hypothecation is illegal."}]}, {"id": "7.28", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "redlining."}, {"label": "b", "text": "usury."}, {"label": "c", "text": "profit-taking."}, {"label": "d", "text": "nothing; there are no legal limits to interest rates."}]}, {"id": "7.29", "question": "advance amount of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$3,600."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$750."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$7,500."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$6,000."}]}, {"id": "7.30", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an amortized loan is paid off over the loan period."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a balloon loan always has a shorter loan term."}, {"label": "c", "text": "an amortized loan requires interest-payments."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a balloon loan must be retired in five years."}]}, {"id": "7.31", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "it is not assignable."}, {"label": "b", "text": "it must be accompanied by a mortgage."}, {"label": "c", "text": "it is a negotiable instrument."}, {"label": "d", "text": "it may not be prepaid."}]}, {"id": "7.32", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "may retain any overage in the escrow account."}, {"label": "b", "text": "may inspect the property before returning legal title."}, {"label": "c", "text": "may be entitled to charge the borrower a small fee to close the loan."}, {"label": "d", "text": "may be required to execute a release of mortgage document."}]}, {"id": "7.33", "question": "documentation, usually including", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "an appraisal report."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a criminal record report."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a subordination agreement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a default recourse waiver."}]}, {"id": "7.34", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "points, interest rate, and loan term."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the location of the mortgaged property, the borrower's cash, and the amount of the borrower's\nequity."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the ability to re-pay, the value of the collateral, and the profitability of the loan."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the amount of the loan, the borrower's income, and the down payment."}]}, {"id": "7.35", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "they don't want to lend borrowers any more money than necessary."}, {"label": "b", "text": "they want to ensure there is more than enough collateral to cover the loan amount."}, {"label": "c", "text": "borrowers can only afford to borrow a portion of the entire purchase price."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the higher the loan-to-value ratio, the more profitable the loan."}]}, {"id": "7.36", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "extend equal credit to all prospective borrowers."}, {"label": "b", "text": "consider the income of a spouse in evaluating a family's creditworthiness."}, {"label": "c", "text": "discount the income of a person involved in child-rearing or child-bearing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "specialize in lending activity by geographical area for improved customer service."}]}, {"id": "7.37", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "insure a borrower has the earning power to make the loan payments."}, {"label": "b", "text": "compare a borrower's earnings to the borrower\u2019s short-term debt."}, {"label": "c", "text": "identify the highest possible interest rate that the borrower can afford."}, {"label": "d", "text": "quantify the borrower's assets to the fullest extent."}]}, {"id": "7.38", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "total debt divided by debt payments."}, {"label": "b", "text": "gross income divided by assets."}, {"label": "c", "text": "gross income divided by debts."}, {"label": "d", "text": "debt payments divided by gross income."}]}, {"id": "7.39", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the borrower pays off the note and receives clear title."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the lender issues a firm loan commitment."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the parties complete all loan origination documents and the loan is funded."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the borrower's loan application is complete and the file closed."}]}, {"id": "7.40", "question": "percentage rate to a borrower before funding a loan?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The Equal Credit Opportunity Act."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Truth-in-Lending laws and Regulation Z."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The Real Estate Settlement and Procedures Act."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Federal Fair Housing Laws."}]}, {"id": "7.41", "question": "potential borrowers?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The Equal Credit Opportunity Act."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Truth-in-Lending laws."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The Real Estate Settlement and Procedures Act."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Federal Fair Housing Laws."}]}, {"id": "7.42", "question": "borrower and forbid them to pay kickbacks for referrals?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The Equal Credit Opportunity Act."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Truth-in-Lending laws."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the Real Estate Settlement and Procedures Act."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Federal Fair Housing Laws."}]}, {"id": "7.43", "question": "supply?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Selling securities, printing money, and controlling lending underwriting requirements."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Buying securities, changing the discount rate, and controlling banking reserves."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Printing money, changing interest rates, and selling T-bills."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Controlling the prime rate, trading securities, and purchasing loans."}]}, {"id": "7.44", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It cycles funds back to primary lenders so they can make more loans."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It issues second mortgages and sells them in the home equity market."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It lends funds to banks so they can make more loans."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It pays off defaulted loans made by primary mortgage lenders."}]}, {"id": "7.45", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, and Ginnie Mae."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Fannie Mae, GMAC, and MGIC."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Freddie Mac, FHA, and VA."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, and the Federal Reserve."}]}, {"id": "7.46", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It guarantees FHA-backed and VA-backed loans."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It insures FHA-backed and VA-backed loans."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It purchases FHA-backed and VA-backed loans."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It originates FHA-backed and VA-backed loans."}]}, {"id": "7.47", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It guarantees loans made by approved lenders."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It insures loans made by approved lenders."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It purchases loans made by approved lenders."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It originates loans made by approved lenders."}]}, {"id": "7.48", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It guarantees loans made by approved lenders."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It insures loans made by approved lenders."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It purchases loans made by approved lenders."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It originates loans made by approved lenders."}]}, {"id": "7.49", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "loan funds are disbursed to the borrower on a graduated basis."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the interest rate periodically increases in graduated phases."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the loan payments gradually increase."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the loan payments gradually increase and the loan term gradually decreases."}]}, {"id": "7.50", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the lender lowers the interest rate on a loan in exchange for a prepayment of principal."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the borrower pays additional interest at the onset in order to obtain a lower interest rate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the lender requires the borrower to buy down the price of the property by increasing the down\npayment."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the borrower pays the lender additional funds to buy down the term of the loan."}]}, {"id": "7.51", "question": "downpayment. Which of the following will Steve's lender most likely require in order to approve\nthis loan?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A personal guarantee"}, {"label": "b", "text": "A buydown loan as a second lien"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Private mortgage insurance"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Additional points"}]}, {"id": "7.52", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Military veterans from farming families"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Primary medical market lenders"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Economically liquid farmers"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Agribusinesses\n\n\n\nTest 8: Investments; Taxation; Professional Practices"}]}, {"id": "8.1", "question": "When an investor has to pay a lender more to finance the investment than the investment property\ngenerates in income, the investor suffers from", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "negative amortization."}, {"label": "b", "text": "negative leverage."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a reverse mortgage."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a debt investment."}]}, {"id": "8.2", "question": "Cost recovery is allowed as a federal tax deduction on", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "principal residences that do not have a home office."}, {"label": "b", "text": "income properties."}, {"label": "c", "text": "land."}, {"label": "d", "text": "commercial properties owned by the federal government."}]}, {"id": "8.3", "question": "A homeowner paid $200,000 for a house three years ago. The house sells today for $239,000. How\nmuch has the property appreciated?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "8.4 %."}, {"label": "b", "text": "6.5 %."}, {"label": "c", "text": "19.5 %."}, {"label": "d", "text": "16.3 %."}]}, {"id": "8.4", "question": "The primary tax benefit in owning a non-income property such as a residence is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "depreciation of improvements."}, {"label": "b", "text": "appreciation of land."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a deduction for costs of operating the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a deduction for mortgage interest."}]}, {"id": "8.5", "question": "A house sold for $250,000. The seller paid a brokerage commission of six percent, legal fees of\n$600, and had other closing costs of $1,500. What are net proceeds from the sale?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$235,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$234,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$233,500."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$232,900."}]}, {"id": "8.6", "question": "A homeowner bought a house five years ago for $450,000. Since then, the homeowner has spent\n$9,000 to pave the driveway and has added a central heating/air conditioning system at a cost of\n$12,000. What is the homeowner's adjusted basis if the house is sold today?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$468,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$471,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$429,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$435,000."}]}, {"id": "8.7", "question": "A homeowner sold her house and realized a net proceeds amount of $420,000. Her adjusted basis in\nthe home was $352,000. She immediately bought another house for $400,000. What was her capital\ngain?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$20,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$48,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$68,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "None."}]}, {"id": "8.8", "question": "After five years of owner-occupancy, Simon Wilson sells his principal residence for a gain of\n$150,000, and the next month buys another principal residence that costs more than the adjusted sale\nprice of the old home. Which of the following is true of the treatment of the tax on gain?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "There is no taxable gain."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It must be paid in the year of the sale."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The homeowner may choose to pay it or defer it."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Tax is due on the difference between the cost of the new home and adjusted basis of the old one."}]}, {"id": "8.9", "question": "Ralph Roberts buys a small office building as an investment and participates actively in the\nmanagement and operation of the building. This is an example of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "syndication."}, {"label": "b", "text": "equity investment."}, {"label": "c", "text": "direct investment."}, {"label": "d", "text": "illiquidity."}]}, {"id": "8.10", "question": "or interest expenses connected with the property. Elmo takes an annual cost recovery expense of\n$5,000. The property has a monthly gross income of $1,500 and monthly operating expenses of\n$500. Elmo's taxable income from this property will be taxed at a rate of 30%. What is the tax\nliability for the year?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$2,100."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$3,600."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$3,900."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$7,000."}]}, {"id": "8.11", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the degree of return is inversely related to the degree of risk."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the more the investor stands to gain, the greater the risk that the investor may lose."}, {"label": "c", "text": "investments requiring intense management have lesser returns."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the more liquid an investment is, the greater the chances are that the investment will not\nappreciate."}]}, {"id": "8.12", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "income and tax benefits."}, {"label": "b", "text": "negative leverage and appreciation."}, {"label": "c", "text": "appreciation and taxation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "positive leverage and prestige."}]}, {"id": "8.13", "question": "to be", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "management intensive."}, {"label": "b", "text": "insensitive to marketing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "vulnerable to seller's markets."}, {"label": "d", "text": "relatively illiquid."}]}, {"id": "8.14", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a riskier investment."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a more management-intensive investment."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a shorter-term investment."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a more leveraged investment."}]}, {"id": "8.15", "question": "marketing and leasing. Two investors manage accounting and finance, and the remaining two run\nthe management office. This is a possible example of", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a general partnership."}, {"label": "b", "text": "a limited partnership."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a real estate investment trust."}, {"label": "d", "text": "an investment conduit."}]}, {"id": "8.16", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "gross income minus expenses plus land and building depreciation."}, {"label": "b", "text": "gross income minus expenses minus land and building depreciation."}, {"label": "c", "text": "gross income minus building depreciation plus land depreciation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "gross income minus expenses minus building depreciation."}]}, {"id": "8.17", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "deduct principal and interest payments from income."}, {"label": "b", "text": "deduct principal payments from income."}, {"label": "c", "text": "deduct interest payments from income."}, {"label": "d", "text": "deduct principal and interest payments from income and capital gain."}]}, {"id": "8.18", "question": "of the tax treatment of this property?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The owner may deduct the property's interest and principal from ordinary income."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The owner may depreciate the property and deduct depreciation expenses from ordinary income."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The owner can deduct any capital gain when the property is sold."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The owner may be able to avoid capital gain tax when the property is sold."}]}, {"id": "8.19", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "may be deducted from personal income."}, {"label": "b", "text": "may be deducted from the property's income."}, {"label": "c", "text": "may be deducted from the sale price for gains tax purposes."}, {"label": "d", "text": "may be deducted from the adjusted basis for gains tax purposes."}]}, {"id": "8.20", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the sum of the beginning basis plus gain."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the difference between amount realized and adjusted basis."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the sum of net sale proceeds and capital gain."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the difference between net sale proceeds and capital gain."}]}, {"id": "8.21", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The Internal Revenue Service."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A utility company."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A tax district."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A court of law."}]}, {"id": "8.22", "question": "taxation in many areas. The protected categories usually include", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "recreational properties."}, {"label": "b", "text": "properties owned by a government agency."}, {"label": "c", "text": "properties that comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act."}, {"label": "d", "text": "properties occupied by single-parent families."}]}, {"id": "8.23", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It modifies a local tax rate to bring it into conformity with statutory tax rates."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It changes the assessed value of an individual property to make it reflect the assessed values of\nother properties in the same neighborhood."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It adjusts assessments in a locality to make them more consistent with an average level for the\nstate or other higher level jurisdiction."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It adjusts the amount of the homestead exemption in a certain area to make it proportionally\nequivalent to the average homestead exemption in other areas."}]}, {"id": "8.24", "question": "$20,000,000. What is the tax base of the area?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$20,000,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$200,000,000."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$2,000,000,000."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$200,000,000,000."}]}, {"id": "8.25", "question": "$1,000, and the fire protection district, taxed at $2.00 per $1,000. How much does the taxpayer\nhave to pay for these two items if the property's taxable value is $441,000?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$4,701."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$471."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$4,230."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$1,323."}]}, {"id": "8.26", "question": "Mary's property has 38 feet of front footage. If the cost of the project to be paid by a special\nassessment is $30,000, what will Mary's assessment be?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$6,000."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$5,700."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$789."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$1,579."}]}, {"id": "8.27", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A conveyance instrument for a property that is sold to enforce a tax lien."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A document recorded in title records showing that property taxes have been paid."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A notice to a homeowner that a tax lien has been entered against the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A document that gives a municipal authority the power to collect an individual tax bill."}]}, {"id": "8.28", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "a legal right of rescission."}, {"label": "b", "text": "an equitable right to acquire title."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a right of homestead exclusion."}, {"label": "d", "text": "a statutory right of redemption."}]}, {"id": "8.29", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the jurisdiction's annual budget times the tax rate."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the total of all assessed values of properties minus exemptions."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the total amount of ad valorem taxes required by the budget."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the municipality's budget multiplied times the millage rate."}]}, {"id": "8.30", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "dividing the tax requirement by the tax base."}, {"label": "b", "text": "multiplying each district's tax rate times the market value of the property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "multiplying each district's tax rate times the taxable value of the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "averaging the tax rate for each tax district, and multiplying the average tax rate times the assessed\nvalue."}]}, {"id": "8.31", "question": "the", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Civil Rights Act of 1866."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Civil Rights Act of 1968."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Executive Order 11063 of 1962."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Title VIII amendment to the Fair Housing Act."}]}, {"id": "8.32", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "race only."}, {"label": "b", "text": "religion and gender only."}, {"label": "c", "text": "race, color, religion, and national origin."}, {"label": "d", "text": "age and gender only."}]}, {"id": "8.33", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Telling prospective buyers about the positive and negative aspects of a certain neighborhood."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Telling a prospective seller that now would be a good time to put a property on the market."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Advertising a property as available to individuals of a particular race."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Telling a prospective buyer that the agent is too busy to show the buyer properties personally on a\ngiven day."}]}, {"id": "8.34", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "An agent shows a minority home buyer properties located in a neighborhood where there are no\nother minority homeowners."}, {"label": "b", "text": "An agent persuades a minority home buyer to avoid looking in a neighborhood where there are\nno minority homeowners."}, {"label": "c", "text": "An agent persuades a family to put their house on the market because ethnic minority families are\nbeginning to move into the neighborhood."}, {"label": "d", "text": "An agent persuades a minority home buyer to buy a property located in an area where most of the\nhomeowners belong to minority groups."}]}, {"id": "8.35", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The Home Mortgage Disclosure Act."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The Civil Rights Act of 1866."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The Americans with Disabilities Act."}]}, {"id": "8.36", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "all single-family residences."}, {"label": "b", "text": "all privately owned single-family residences."}, {"label": "c", "text": "privately owned single-family residences listed with a broker."}, {"label": "d", "text": "privately owned single-family residences for sale by owner."}]}, {"id": "8.37", "question": "in the house and ask the agent the price. The agent states the price as $420,000. According to the\nfair housing laws, such an action is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "illegal, because the agent changed the terms of the sale to discourage this particular couple."}, {"label": "b", "text": "illegal, because the agent violated the listing agreement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "legal, because the quoted price increase did not exceed 10% of the listing price."}, {"label": "d", "text": "legal, because the increased price does not necessarily exclude the couple."}]}, {"id": "8.38", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A broker, following the instructions of the seller, advertises the property as for sale to Christian\nfamilies only."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A home seller, acting without a broker, places a \"for sale-- mature, single men only\" sign in front\nof the house."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The owner of four rental houses advertises one of the properties for rent to married couples, no\nchildren, no pets."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The owner of a duplex who resides in one of the units refuses to rent the other unit to a nonChristian."}]}, {"id": "8.39", "question": "because she is a woman. What actions should she take if she wants legal satisfaction for her\ncomplaint?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "File charges of illegal discrimination with the police department that has jurisdiction over the\nlocal area."}, {"label": "b", "text": "File a complaint with HUD and/or file suit against the offending parties in a state or federal court\nwithin the prescribed time period."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Wait two years and then file a civil suit in federal court."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Sue HUD for damages under the Civil rights Act of 1866."}]}, {"id": "8.40", "question": "in the neighborhood to sell to members of a certain ethnic group. What should Shannon do about\nthis condition?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Inform Scott that the condition is illegal and that she cannot comply with it."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Note the condition on the listing agreement and have Scott initial it."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Pretend that she did not hear the condition and proceed to market the property to all groups."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Tell Scott that she will try to discourage members of that group from looking at the property, but\nthat she cannot control cooperating brokers."}]}, {"id": "8.41", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "advertise that the property is not available to anyone requiring wheelchair access."}, {"label": "b", "text": "refuse to rent to aliens."}, {"label": "c", "text": "require families without children to pay the same security deposit that families with children must\npay."}, {"label": "d", "text": "require tenants to move out when they become 62 years old."}]}, {"id": "8.42", "question": "belief that they cause damage. Under what conditions would federal fair housing laws allow Gough\nto rent on these terms?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The owner has a consistent no-children policy in all his rental properties."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The owner can prove that costs to repair damage caused by previous tenants with children\nexceeded the tenants' security deposit."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It is a single-family house that is part of a federally-designated planned unit development."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It is a single-family house, and the owner owns only one other rental home in addition to his own\nresidence."}]}, {"id": "8.43", "question": "status, and family status?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Executive Order 11063."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the Civil Rights Act of 1968."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Jones v Mayer."}]}, {"id": "8.44", "question": "shows the family all available properties in a neighborhood of families with similar backgrounds.\nAmbrose does not mention a number of homes in the family's price range in other neighborhoods.\nThis agent could be liable for", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "blockbusting."}, {"label": "b", "text": "providing unequal services."}, {"label": "c", "text": "steering."}, {"label": "d", "text": "nothing; his services were legal and acceptable."}]}, {"id": "8.45", "question": "engage in lengthy conversation or show him any properties. A second minority party visits the\noffice the next day. The agent is very forthcoming, and shows the person five prospective\nproperties. This agent could be liable for", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "providing unequal services."}, {"label": "b", "text": "steering."}, {"label": "c", "text": "misrepresentation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "nothing; both parties were minorities, and therefore no discrimination occurred."}]}, {"id": "8.46", "question": "employed but pregnant and unmarried minority woman. This agent could be liable for", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "discriminatory misrepresentation by omission."}, {"label": "b", "text": "steering."}, {"label": "c", "text": "violating fiduciary duty."}, {"label": "d", "text": "nothing: an agent may show or not show any property at his or her discretion."}]}, {"id": "8.47", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "With a newly-constructed single family home"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Immediately following the closing of any residential property"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Prior to the sale of an occupied 1-4 unit dwelling"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Prior to the closing of any commercial or residential re-sale"}]}, {"id": "8.48", "question": "Disclosure form", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "can be substituted by the licensee\u2019s material facts disclosure form."}, {"label": "b", "text": "does not have to be completed prior to closing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "can be completed by either the seller or the licensee."}, {"label": "d", "text": "must still be completed according to local requirements."}]}, {"id": "8.49", "question": "Seller\u2019s Property Condition Disclosure form?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A house has a leaking roof."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A basement floods."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A previous occupant died in the house."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A previous occupant contaminated the house by manufacturing methamphetamine in the\nbasement."}]}, {"id": "8.50", "question": "Jessica wishes to purchase seller Ryan's house. In putting together her offer documents, Jessica\nincludes a handwritten note along with her full-price offer saying how much she loves the property\nand how she can imagine living at the home for the rest of her life. This personal note included with\nthe offer is typically referred to as a", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "homestead pledge."}, {"label": "b", "text": "guaranteed resident assurance."}, {"label": "c", "text": "waiver of inspection."}, {"label": "d", "text": "love letter."}]}, {"id": "8.51", "question": "Real estate wholesaling is a method of profiting from a real estate transaction without actually\nbuying any real estate. The wholesaler finds a willing seller, puts the property under contract, and\nfinds a third-party buyer willing to buy at a higher price than what the wholesaler has agreed to pay\nthe original seller. How are some states fighting the practice of real estate wholesaling?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "By requiring the wholesaler to have a real estate license"}, {"label": "b", "text": "By prohibiting the assignment of contracts within 10 days of closing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "By requiring any property to be fully occupied by any particular owner for 300 days"}, {"label": "d", "text": "By banning wholesaling on transactions of $250,000 or more\n\n\n\nTest 9: Closings; Risk Management; Property Management"}]}, {"id": "9.1", "question": "The conditions of an escrow agreement cannot be met and the related transaction cannot be\ncompleted. In such a case, the escrow agent", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "levies a fine against the defaulting party."}, {"label": "b", "text": "assigns his or her fiduciary responsibilities to the seller's broker."}, {"label": "c", "text": "returns funds to the buyer."}, {"label": "d", "text": "cancels the sale contract and destroys the transaction documents."}]}, {"id": "9.2", "question": "To avoid violating the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act, parties who are providing services to\nthe buyer or seller in a transaction must", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "be paid before the closing date for any service they provide."}, {"label": "b", "text": "inform the closing agent of the cost of their services at least one week before the closing date."}, {"label": "c", "text": "receive payment only from the funds held in escrow, not directly from buyer or seller."}, {"label": "d", "text": "disclose in writing any business relationships they have with other parties involved in the\ntransaction."}]}, {"id": "9.3", "question": "A certain item is to be prorated between a buyer and seller. If no outside party is concerned, which\nof the following statements is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The item must be prorated and recorded as a debit to one party and a credit to the other party for\nthe same amount."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The item must be prorated and recorded as a debit to one party; the remainder is recorded as a\ncredit to the other party."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The party who is owed money receives a credit for the entire item and a debit for the prorated\namount."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The party who owes money receives a debit for the portion owed and a credit for the portion that\nis not owed."}]}, {"id": "9.4", "question": "An item is said to be paid in arrears if it is normally paid", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "on a monthly or yearly basis."}, {"label": "b", "text": "at some time after the expense is incurred."}, {"label": "c", "text": "only after it is billed."}, {"label": "d", "text": "whenever it is incurred."}]}, {"id": "9.5", "question": "A seller received a rental payment of $900 in advance. At closing, the seller has earned only $320 of\nthis rent. What should appear on the closing statement?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A debit to the seller and credit to the buyer for $320."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A debit to the seller for $580 and a credit to the buyer for $320."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A debit to the seller for $320 and a credit to the buyer for $900."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A debit to the seller and credit to the buyer for $580."}]}, {"id": "9.6", "question": "A buyer will receive a water bill for an estimated $100 at the end of the month. At closing, the seller\nhas used an estimated $43 in water. What should appear on the closing statement?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A debit to the seller and credit to the buyer for $57."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A debit to the seller and credit to the buyer for $43."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A debit to the buyer and credit to the seller for $57."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A debit to the buyer and credit to the seller for $43."}]}, {"id": "9.7", "question": "A sale transaction closes on April 1, the ninety-first day of the tax year. The day of closing belongs\nto the seller. Real estate taxes for the year, not yet billed, are expected to be $2,190. According to\nthe 365-day method, what is the seller's share of the tax bill?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,644.00."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$546.00."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$959.30"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$1,364.66."}]}, {"id": "9.8", "question": "A sale transaction closes on July 4 (184th day of the year). The day of closing belongs to the seller.\nOn January 1, the seller paid a hazard insurance premium of $3,750 for the calendar year.\nAccording to the 12-month/30-day method, what is the seller's share of the insurance premium?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,833.33."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$1,875.00."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$1,890.50."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$1,916.67."}]}, {"id": "9.9", "question": "Waldo is buying Marianne's house. The closing date (day belongs to seller) of the sale transaction is\nSeptember 1 (day 244 of the year). Current Year real estate taxes are $1,100 (will be billed to buyer\nnext year). Use the 365-day method for prorating. What is Marianne's share of the real estate taxes?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$364.66."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$367.67."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$732.33."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$735.34."}]}, {"id": "9.10", "question": "September 1 (day 244 of the year). Existing hazard insurance of $350 has been paid by John through\nDecember 31. Use the 365-day method for prorating. What is Christie's share of the existing hazard\ninsurance already paid in full?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$116.03."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$117.99."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$232.01."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$233.97."}]}, {"id": "9.11", "question": "September 1 (day 244 of the year). The buyer's loan amount is $787,500 (90%; 30 years @ 8%).\nThe monthly payment on this loan is $5,778.40, with $5,250 going to interest in the first month. At\nclosing, Julie must pre-pay interest for the period of Sept. 2-Sept. 30. Use the 365-day method for\nprorating. What is Julie\u2019s prepaid interest amount?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$5,075.00."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$5,250.00."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$5,431.00."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$5,585.80."}]}, {"id": "9.12", "question": "points at closing. How much will Melissa pay for points?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,575."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$1,775."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$17,750."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$8,875."}]}, {"id": "9.13", "question": "6%. How much will Terrell pay the broker?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$62,500."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$5,250."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$9,450."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$22,500."}]}, {"id": "9.14", "question": "customary in the area. In this case,", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the buyer and seller must amend the contract before closing."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the contract is voidable, since the seller must pay the expense."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the buyer may pay or not pay the expense, at his or her option."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the buyer must pay the expense."}]}, {"id": "9.15", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the excess of the buyer's debits over the buyer's credits."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the excess of the buyer's credits over the buyer's debits."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the excess of the seller's debits over the seller's credits."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the excess of the seller's credits over the seller's debits."}]}, {"id": "9.16", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "failure to disclose an environmental condition."}, {"label": "b", "text": "antitrust violations."}, {"label": "c", "text": "mishandling of earnest money deposits."}, {"label": "d", "text": "negligence, error or omission in carrying out professional services."}]}, {"id": "9.17", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Failing to inform and disclose properly."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Failing to take a personal interest in a transaction."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Acting as an exclusive agent without an oral agency agreement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Forgetting to record the listing agreement."}]}, {"id": "9.18", "question": "licensee may still be subject to legal action for", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "failing to detect customer misrepresentations."}, {"label": "b", "text": "failing to disclose known adverse facts."}, {"label": "c", "text": "relying on publicly available market information."}, {"label": "d", "text": "advising the purchaser to exercise due diligence."}]}, {"id": "9.19", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "use the term \"market value\" whenever possible in the report."}, {"label": "b", "text": "show a low suggested selling price to avoid a complaint of misrepresenting the value."}, {"label": "c", "text": "include the results of a certified appraisal in the analysis."}, {"label": "d", "text": "avoid creating a false impression that the licensee is a certified appraiser."}]}, {"id": "9.20", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "finding a buyer who turns out to be unqualified."}, {"label": "b", "text": "exceeding the authority of the agreement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "showing the property without the presence of the owner."}, {"label": "d", "text": "cooperating with other licensees."}]}, {"id": "9.21", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "use a checklist of all items, contingencies, dates and responsibilities that must be met."}, {"label": "b", "text": "delegate some of your responsibilities to the licensee who represents the other party in the\ncontract."}, {"label": "c", "text": "call the buyer and seller daily to check on progress."}, {"label": "d", "text": "cut the list of necessary tasks down to a few essentials and concentrate on tracking those."}]}, {"id": "9.22", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "once written and signed they cannot be changed except by a lawyer."}, {"label": "b", "text": "real estate licensees may alter forms but not contracts."}, {"label": "c", "text": "whoever originates them can make changes without the risk of unauthorized practice of law."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the principals may make changes as long as they sign or initial each change."}]}, {"id": "9.23", "question": "to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "deal only with consumers who do not belong to a protected class."}, {"label": "b", "text": "obtain education in the content and intent of the laws."}, {"label": "c", "text": "make sure there is always a witness present at all meetings with consumers."}, {"label": "d", "text": "stay away from transactions involving public housing."}]}, {"id": "9.24", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "being present at a conversation where the setting of commission rates is discussed."}, {"label": "b", "text": "being present at a discussion of antitrust laws."}, {"label": "c", "text": "charging a commission rate that happens to be the same as that charged by another firm."}, {"label": "d", "text": "cooperating with another firm to do market research."}]}, {"id": "9.25", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "License discipline, fines, and possible incarceration."}, {"label": "b", "text": "License discipline and fines, but no incarceration."}, {"label": "c", "text": "License discipline only."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Fines only."}]}, {"id": "9.26", "question": "misrepresentation is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "measuring and reporting property dimensions."}, {"label": "b", "text": "describing properties and amenities."}, {"label": "c", "text": "stating that a client should seek legal counsel."}, {"label": "d", "text": "making statements about the presence or absence of hazardous substances."}]}, {"id": "9.27", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "make reports orally only, never in writing."}, {"label": "b", "text": "leave progress reporting to the inspectors and other experts."}, {"label": "c", "text": "advise the client that it is company policy to make no progress reports until the contingency\nperiod is over."}, {"label": "d", "text": "avoid speculative statements in all reports"}]}, {"id": "9.28", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It guarantees that a buyer will have a loan."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It reduces the chance of presenting an offer from an unqualified buyer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It relieves the licensee of his or her due diligence responsibilities."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It allows the licensee to avoid asking embarrassing questions."}]}, {"id": "9.29", "question": "is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "trust fund handling."}, {"label": "b", "text": "office management."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the agency relationship."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the closing process."}]}, {"id": "9.30", "question": "licensee is a certified appraiser is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "performing a comparative market analysis."}, {"label": "b", "text": "writing property advertisements."}, {"label": "c", "text": "presenting written offers."}, {"label": "d", "text": "researching ownership documents."}]}, {"id": "9.31", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "describe the property in excessively glowing terms."}, {"label": "b", "text": "fail to appear at the same time in all available media."}, {"label": "c", "text": "omit any mention of the owner\u2019s main selling points."}, {"label": "d", "text": "make a substantial misrepresentation."}]}, {"id": "9.32", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "non-binding"}, {"label": "b", "text": "partnership"}, {"label": "c", "text": "fiduciary"}, {"label": "d", "text": "subagency"}]}, {"id": "9.33", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "obtaining construction loans for the principal."}, {"label": "b", "text": "financial reporting to the principal."}, {"label": "c", "text": "finding a buyer for the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "maintaining good standing in a managers\u2019 professional association."}]}, {"id": "9.34", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the total of scheduled rents."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the total of all rents and revenues generated by a property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "potential gross income minus debt service and reserves."}, {"label": "d", "text": "revenue from all sources minus losses from uncollected rents, vacancies, and evictions."}]}, {"id": "9.35", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "cost per tenant prospect generated per lease."}, {"label": "b", "text": "number of ads produced per marketing dollar."}, {"label": "c", "text": "dollars expended per square foot of vacant space."}, {"label": "d", "text": "percentage of reserves expended on marketing."}]}, {"id": "9.36", "question": "manager needs to", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "lower rental rates."}, {"label": "b", "text": "raise rental rates."}, {"label": "c", "text": "find better tenants."}, {"label": "d", "text": "improve management quality."}]}, {"id": "9.37", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Constructive, deconstructive, and reconstructive"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Routine, preventive, and corrective"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Scheduled, planned, and improvised"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Emergency, elective, and optional"}]}, {"id": "9.38", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "ensure that disabled employees have the same level of access to facilities that all employees have."}, {"label": "b", "text": "hire the disabled whenever possible."}, {"label": "c", "text": "remove all existing barriers to the free movement of disabled persons within the property,\nregardless of the cost."}, {"label": "d", "text": "remodel the ground floor of the property in accordance with ADA standards if it was built before\n1978."}]}, {"id": "9.39", "question": "of the property\u2019s", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "replacement value."}, {"label": "b", "text": "reproduction value."}, {"label": "c", "text": "original cost."}, {"label": "d", "text": "depreciated basis."}]}, {"id": "9.40", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "rents collected from tenants."}, {"label": "b", "text": "cash for the management firm\u2019s operating expenses."}, {"label": "c", "text": "security deposits."}, {"label": "d", "text": "capital contributions from the property owner."}]}, {"id": "9.41", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Universal"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Specific"}, {"label": "c", "text": "General"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Vicarious"}]}, {"id": "9.42", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The tenant pays a base rent plus some or all of the operating expenses."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The tenant pays a fixed rent, and the landlord pays all operating expenses."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The tenant pays a base rent plus an amount based on income generated in the leased space."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The tenant pays a rent that increases at specified times over the lease term."}]}, {"id": "9.43", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the lessee is required to buy it from the landlord."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the landlord is required to remove it."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the lease is invalidated because of an incomplete property description."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the property manager does not have to maintain it."}]}, {"id": "9.44", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "provide leased space at market rental rates."}, {"label": "b", "text": "deliver a habitable property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "keep the rental space freshly painted."}, {"label": "d", "text": "refrain from entering the leased space at any time during the lease term."}]}, {"id": "9.45", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A landlord obtains a court order to force the tenant to vacate the leased premises."}, {"label": "b", "text": "A court officer forcibly removes the tenant from the premises."}, {"label": "c", "text": "A tenant declares a landlord in default and vacates the leased premises."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A landlord declares a tenant in default and takes possession of the leased premises."}]}, {"id": "9.46", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the competitive market for the property."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the property manager\u2019s career goals."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the property owner\u2019s net worth."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the management firm\u2019s income goals.\n\n\n\nTest 10: Real Estate Math"}]}, {"id": "10.1", "question": "broker 50-50, what did she receive per square foot?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$.023 / SF"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$.046 / SF"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$.037/ SF"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$.002 / SF"}]}, {"id": "10.2", "question": "to build a 2,500 SF home on a 1.5 acre corner lot. The custom builder can build the home for $135 /\nSF. What will the completed property cost the Grandersons?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$359,170"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$370,170"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$32,670"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$374,070"}]}, {"id": "10.3", "question": "approximate percentage of the lot will be left over, if any, when he has completed the construction?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "12%"}, {"label": "b", "text": "88%"}, {"label": "c", "text": "3%"}, {"label": "d", "text": "15%"}]}, {"id": "10.4", "question": "will take up about 30% of this overall area. If the minimum lot size is to be 12,000 SF, how many\nlots can the developer have on this property?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "42"}, {"label": "b", "text": "487"}, {"label": "c", "text": "40"}, {"label": "d", "text": "57"}]}, {"id": "10.5", "question": "of insulation would do the job. The walls are all 9\u2019 high and respectively measure 13\u2019, 13\u2019, 18\u2019, and\n18\u2019 in length. How many rolls will she need if each roll measures 3\u201d x 2\u2019 x 50\u2019?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "6"}, {"label": "b", "text": "56"}, {"label": "c", "text": "5"}, {"label": "d", "text": "9"}]}, {"id": "10.6", "question": "figures she\u2019ll mulch an area 8\u2019 in width to form a big rectangle all around the perimeter. What is the\nsquare footage of the resulting mulched area?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "64 SF"}, {"label": "b", "text": "2,576 SF"}, {"label": "c", "text": "1,824 SF"}, {"label": "d", "text": "1,376 SF"}]}, {"id": "10.7", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "20 acres"}, {"label": "b", "text": "40 acres"}, {"label": "c", "text": "60 acres"}, {"label": "d", "text": "5 acres"}]}, {"id": "10.8", "question": "Section 4. How many acres is that property?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "4 acres"}, {"label": "b", "text": "40 acres"}, {"label": "c", "text": "10 acres"}, {"label": "d", "text": "8 acres"}]}, {"id": "10.9", "question": "SF / month rent plus 1.75% of the store\u2019s gross income. If monthly sales averaged $41,500 last\nyear, how much annual rent did Yard of Pizza pay last year?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$38,955"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$43,420"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$30,240"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$21,525"}]}, {"id": "10.10", "question": "was the average appreciation over the 3-year period expressed as a decimal?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "5.04%"}, {"label": "b", "text": "15.24%"}, {"label": "c", "text": "7.56%"}, {"label": "d", "text": "4.8%"}]}, {"id": "10.11", "question": "much has the property appreciated?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "23%"}, {"label": "b", "text": "77%"}, {"label": "c", "text": "29%"}, {"label": "d", "text": "123%"}]}, {"id": "10.12", "question": "offer as a percent of the listing price?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "87%"}, {"label": "b", "text": "91%"}, {"label": "c", "text": "94%"}, {"label": "d", "text": "106%"}]}, {"id": "10.13", "question": "gross income of $30,000, vacancy and credit losses of $1,500, and operating expenses of $10,000.\nUsing a capitalization rate of 9%, what is the indicated value (to the nearest $1,000)?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$206,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$167,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$222,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$180,000"}]}, {"id": "10.14", "question": "the property using the income capitalization method is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$625,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$375,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$3,750,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$937,500"}]}, {"id": "10.15", "question": "straight-line method of depreciation, what is the depreciated value of the roof after 3 years?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$16,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$13,600"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$18,400"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$12,000"}]}, {"id": "10.16", "question": "SF office area. Lee paid $280,000 for his home, and he figures the land portion carries about 25% of\nthat value. If Lee depreciates on a 39-year basis, how much can he write off for his home office\ndepreciation per year?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,077"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$1,436"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$5,384"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$2,108"}]}, {"id": "10.17", "question": "$80,000 and the replacement cost of the improvements is $350,000. Total depreciation from all\ncauses is $54,000. What is the indicated value of the property?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$296,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$456,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$324,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$376,000"}]}, {"id": "10.18", "question": "the land @ $100,000, but land has appreciated 25% over this period. The investor has used a 40year straight-line depreciation method to depreciate the property. What is its current value using the\ncost approach?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$437,500"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$462,500"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$475,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$546,875"}]}, {"id": "10.19", "question": "What is its monthly gross rent multiplier?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "80"}, {"label": "b", "text": ".01"}, {"label": "c", "text": "110"}, {"label": "d", "text": "125"}]}, {"id": "10.20", "question": "from market data is 14.7. What estimated sale price (to the nearest $1,000) is indicated?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$297,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$486,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$582,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$519,000"}]}, {"id": "10.21", "question": "is the first month\u2019s interest payment?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,800"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$500"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$2,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$1,500"}]}, {"id": "10.22", "question": "payment is $1,580, how much is the loan\u2019s principal balance (to the nearest $1,000)?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$444,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$358,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$190,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$292,000"}]}, {"id": "10.23", "question": "her new home loan. Assuming this is an interest-only loan, and the principal balance is $249,000,\nwhat interest rate is Amanda getting?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "4.82%"}, {"label": "b", "text": "5.03%"}, {"label": "c", "text": "6.25%"}, {"label": "d", "text": "3.69%"}]}, {"id": "10.24", "question": "monthly payments are $1,724, how much interest do the Keegans pay in the second month of the\nloan?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,748.33"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$1,456.95"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$1,458.33"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$1,724.00"}]}, {"id": "10.25", "question": "One option is an interest-only loan for 5 years @ 6.5% interest with no points, and the second, a", "answers": []}, {"id": "6.25", "question": "Greys less total interest, and by how much?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The first option, by $150."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The second option, by 150."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The second option, by $750."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Both options charge the same amount of interest."}]}, {"id": "10.26", "question": "many points did he pay?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "1.4 points"}, {"label": "b", "text": "1.67 points"}, {"label": "c", "text": "2.48 points"}, {"label": "d", "text": "1.5 points"}]}, {"id": "10.27", "question": "", "answers": []}, {"id": "1.5", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$450"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$4,500"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$4,875"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$7,500"}]}, {"id": "10.28", "question": "lender requires an 80% loan-to-value ratio. How much can the borrower pay for a property and still\nqualify for this loan amount?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$414,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$312,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$487,500"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$510,000"}]}, {"id": "10.29", "question": "interest rate is 6.75%. If she obtained a 75% loan, what was the purchase price?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$313,333"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$31,604"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$379,259"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$256,000"}]}, {"id": "10.30", "question": "to pay for monthly housing expense to qualify for a loan if the lender uses an income ratio of 30%?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$2,160"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$1,900"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$1,215"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$4,433"}]}, {"id": "10.31", "question": "has depreciated the property for the past 10 years on a 39-year straight-line schedule. If he sells the\nproperty this year and realizes $780,000, what is his capital gain?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$253,846"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$274,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$100,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$179,000"}]}, {"id": "10.32", "question": "$2,000 to build a screened porch and has added a central air-conditioning system at a cost of $5,000.\nWhat is the homeowner's adjusted basis if the house is sold today?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$256,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$257,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$244,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$245,000"}]}, {"id": "10.33", "question": "$231,000. She immediately bought another house for $301,000. What was her capital gain?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$265,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$36,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$34,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "None"}]}, {"id": "10.34", "question": "The following year she had a new roof put on, at a cost of $15,000. What is Debra's adjusted basis\nin the house if she now sells the house for $450,000?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$87,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$288,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$303,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$375,000"}]}, {"id": "10.35", "question": "priced at $360,000 has gross income of $60,000 and expenses of $22,000. Approximately how\nmuch too high or too low is the price of this property for the investor to obtain her desired return\nexactly?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,000 overpriced."}, {"label": "b", "text": "$8,000 underpriced."}, {"label": "c", "text": "$15,000 overpriced."}, {"label": "d", "text": "$16,000 underpriced."}]}, {"id": "10.36", "question": "loves the property, but he knows he needs to make a return of at least 8% to satisfy his partners. If\nthe building is 25,000 SF, rents for $10/SF per year, has 5% vacancy, and annual expenses of\n$70,000, should he buy it? What is his return?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "No, since he will yield 2.00%."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Yes, since he will yield 8.375%."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Yes, since he will yield 8%."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Yes, since he will yield 9.125%."}]}, {"id": "10.37", "question": "interest expenses connected with the property. Chad takes an annual cost recovery expense of\n$7,000. The property has a monthly gross income of $1,650 and monthly operating expenses of\n$600. Chad's taxable income from this property will be taxed at a rate of 30%. What is the tax\nliability for the year?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,680"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$5,940"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$2,100"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$7,000"}]}, {"id": "10.38", "question": "$30,000, and annual cost recovery of $7,000. The property's tax rate is 28%. What is the property's\nannual tax on income?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$14,550"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$40,040"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$10,640"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$2,240"}]}, {"id": "10.39", "question": "subdividing, the investor was able to sell each lot for $230,000. Excluding commissions and closing\ncosts, what per cent profit did the investor realize?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "0%"}, {"label": "b", "text": "45%"}, {"label": "c", "text": "23.9%"}, {"label": "d", "text": "31.4%"}]}, {"id": "10.40", "question": "$10,000,000. What is the tax base of the area?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$10,000,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$100,000,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$1,000,000,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$100,000,000,000"}]}, {"id": "10.41", "question": "The homestead exemption is $50,000. Tax rates for the property are 7 mills for schools; 3 mills for\nthe city; 2 mills for the county; and 1 mill for the local community college. What is the\nhomeowner's tax bill?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$2,990"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$3,640"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$2,300"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$4,420"}]}, {"id": "10.42", "question": "property taxes. Assessed valuations are $400,000,000, and exemptions total $25,000,000. What\nmust the tax rate be to finance the budget?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "2.00%"}, {"label": "b", "text": "2.13%"}, {"label": "c", "text": "1.32%"}, {"label": "d", "text": "21.33%"}]}, {"id": "10.43", "question": "broker and selling broker agree to share the commission equally. What will the listing agent receive\nif the agent is scheduled to get a 40% share from his broker?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$17,780"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$14,224"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$10,668"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$7,112"}]}, {"id": "10.44", "question": "sells for $325,000. The co-brokerage split between Paul and Adams is 50-50. Kevin is on a 65%\ncommission schedule with Paul. If the total commission rate is 6.5%, what is Kevin's commission?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$6,866"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$5,282"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$10,563"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$13,731"}]}, {"id": "10.45", "question": "to the seller. Real estate taxes for the year, not yet billed, are expected to be $3,150. According to\nthe 365-day method, what should appear on the closing statement?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A debit to the buyer and credit to the seller for $2,364.62"}, {"label": "b", "text": "A debit to the buyer and credit to the seller for $785.34"}, {"label": "c", "text": "A credit to the buyer and debit to the seller for $785.34"}, {"label": "d", "text": "A credit to the buyer and debit to the seller for $2,364.62"}]}, {"id": "10.46", "question": "September 1 (day 244 of the year). Her loan has a monthly payment of $577.84, with $525 going to\ninterest in the first month. At closing, Alexis must pre-pay interest for the period of Sept. 2-Sept. 30.\nUse the 365-day method for prorating. What is her prepaid interest amount?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$507.50"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$525.00"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$543.10"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$558.58"}]}, {"id": "10.47", "question": "rent of $1,380 on December 1. Assuming the closing day is the buyer's, and that the 365-day\nmethod is used for prorating, which of the following entries would appear on the settlement\nstatement?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Debit seller $667.74."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Credit seller $1,380.00."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Debit buyer $712.26."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Credit buyer $712.26."}]}, {"id": "10.48", "question": "sale price. Title insurance runs $450, and the attorney costs $550. The agent\u2019s commission is 7%,\nand the mortgage balance is $210,000. Annual real estate taxes are estimated to be $4,000, half of\nwhich will have to be charged to the seller. If the seller pays all of these expenses, what will she\nnet at closing?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$86,873"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$88,371"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$81,372"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$86,372"}]}, {"id": "10.49", "question": "commissions and closing costs, and to allow for negotiating room, he wants to get 95% of the listing\nprice as the selling price, what should his listing price be per acre?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$5,750"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$5,882"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$4,250"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$5,848"}]}, {"id": "10.50", "question": "improvements @ 75% of their replacement value. If the Wildes suffer damage estimated at\n$500,000, and they have an 80% co-insurance clause, what will their recovery be from the policy?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Zero"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$531,915"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$500,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$468,750"}]}, {"id": "10.51", "question": "their insurable property, valued at $380,000. They have an 80% co-insurance requirement in the\npolicy. If the family incurs a $300,000 loss, what if any amount will the Uptons recover?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$319,999"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$281,250"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$280,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$375,000\n\n\n\nSection V: Kentucky-Specific\nPractice Tests\nState Test 11: The Kentucky Real Estate Commission"}]}, {"id": "11.1", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Commissioners serve staggered 6-year terms."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Seven members are elected to 5-year terms."}, {"label": "c", "text": "One member must represent the public."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Members are elected to office by the public."}]}, {"id": "11.2", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "enact laws to regulate the real estate industry."}, {"label": "b", "text": "establish uniform standards for brokerage operations such as commissions."}, {"label": "c", "text": "enforce license laws and discipline violators."}, {"label": "d", "text": "provide a central database for licensees to exchange information on the sale or lease of real\nproperty."}]}, {"id": "11.3", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Audit escrow accounts"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Set non-discrimination rules and regulations"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Provide a central database for licensees to list properties for sale or lease"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Establish a code of ethics for licensees to follow"}]}, {"id": "11.4", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The Commission typically resolves disciplinary matters without conducting hearings or\ninvestigations."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The Commission may settle disciplinary matters through informal settlement proceedings."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The Commission must use mediation as the first step in resolving disciplinary matters."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Disciplinary matters must be resolved in court."}]}, {"id": "11.5", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Issue final decisions regarding disciplinary actions and license applications."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Mandate that parties agree to arbitration."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Hear testimony and review evidence."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Subpoena witnesses and create official court records of the proceeding."}]}, {"id": "11.6", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "review evidence and examine witnesses."}, {"label": "b", "text": "issue an injunction to prevent the licensee from working for up to 3 months."}, {"label": "c", "text": "notify other parties to the transaction about the investigation."}, {"label": "d", "text": "publish public notice of the investigation."}]}, {"id": "11.7", "question": "Estate Authority?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The parties have 30 days to appeal a final order."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The parties may request the final order to be submitted to a mediator."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The parties may sue in district court only if the executive director imposes a fine."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The parties may not appeal the executive director\u2019s decision."}]}, {"id": "11.8", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "There is no limit on the amount of damages the fund can award to an individual claimant."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The Commission will permanently revoke the license of a licensee on whose behalf the fund\ncompensates a consumer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The fund may pay claimants compensatory and punitive damages plus interest."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Payment from the fund results in automatic license suspension or revocation until the licensee\nrepays the amount paid plus interest."}]}, {"id": "11.9", "question": "and regulations?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Fines up to $100,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Jail time"}, {"label": "c", "text": "License suspension or revocation"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Restitution"}]}, {"id": "11.10", "question": "Research, and Recovery Fund.", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$1,000"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$20,000"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$60,000"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$80,000"}]}, {"id": "11.11", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "When an alleged escrow account violation has occurred"}, {"label": "b", "text": "When requested by an attorney"}, {"label": "c", "text": "When requested by a complainant"}, {"label": "d", "text": "When a licensee has violated disclosure requirements"}]}, {"id": "11.12", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "They must be filed with the Commission within one year from the date the complainant knew\nabout the violation."}, {"label": "b", "text": "They must be adjudicated in court."}, {"label": "c", "text": "All complaints must be investigated and adjudicated at a hearing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The complaint screening committee makes final decisions about whether to dismiss a complaint\nor impose disciplinary action.\n\n\n\nState Test 12: Requirements for a Kentucky License"}]}, {"id": "12.1", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A lawyer handling a real estate closing for his client"}, {"label": "b", "text": "An individual negotiating the sale of a property for a fee"}, {"label": "c", "text": "A homeowner selling her own home"}, {"label": "d", "text": "A trustee listing a deceased individual\u2019s home for sale"}]}, {"id": "12.2", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "principal broker."}, {"label": "b", "text": "office manager."}, {"label": "c", "text": "associate broker."}, {"label": "d", "text": "salesperson."}]}, {"id": "12.3", "question": "education.", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "40 hours"}, {"label": "b", "text": "80 hours"}, {"label": "c", "text": "96 hours"}, {"label": "d", "text": "120 hours"}]}, {"id": "12.4", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "They must have worked as a sales associate during the prior 24 months, working at least 20 hours\nper week."}, {"label": "b", "text": "They must have worked as a sales associate during the prior 5 years, working at least 20 hours\nper week."}, {"label": "c", "text": "They must have worked as a licensee during the prior 6 years, working at least 30 hours per\nweek."}, {"label": "d", "text": "They must have worked as a sales associate for at least 6 months."}]}, {"id": "12.5", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "pass the Kentucky state license exam."}, {"label": "b", "text": "pass the national and Kentucky state license exam."}, {"label": "c", "text": "pass the national section of the license exam."}, {"label": "d", "text": "not re-take either the national or state license exam since the applicant holds a license in the\nresident state."}]}, {"id": "12.6", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "complete all CE requirements prior to becoming inactive."}, {"label": "b", "text": "obtain prior approval from the principal broker."}, {"label": "c", "text": "obtain extended reporting period insurance for 1 year."}, {"label": "d", "text": "engage in limited brokerage activity while the license is inactive."}]}, {"id": "12.7", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "within 2 years of receiving or activating their license."}, {"label": "b", "text": "within every 2-year license term."}, {"label": "c", "text": "within 60 days from the initial license date."}, {"label": "d", "text": "within 12 months after the initial license issue date."}]}, {"id": "12.8", "question": "another broker or place the license on inactive status.", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "15"}, {"label": "b", "text": "20"}, {"label": "c", "text": "30"}, {"label": "d", "text": "60"}]}, {"id": "12.9", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "every 12 months prior to the license expiration date."}, {"label": "b", "text": "by December 31 each year."}, {"label": "c", "text": "by December 31 every 3 years."}, {"label": "d", "text": "by March 31 every 3 years."}]}, {"id": "12.10", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "December 31 each year."}, {"label": "b", "text": "March 31 of the renewal year."}, {"label": "c", "text": "September 30 of the renewal year."}, {"label": "d", "text": "January 1 of the renewal year."}]}, {"id": "12.11", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "every year."}, {"label": "b", "text": "every 2 years."}, {"label": "c", "text": "every 3 years."}, {"label": "d", "text": "every 4 years."}]}, {"id": "12.12", "question": "license?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Reactivate the license within 1 year by paying the delinquent renewal fee."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Meet the requirements for a new license."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Complete extra continuing education and apply for reactivation of the license within 1 year."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Nothing; canceled licensees may never be reactivated."}]}, {"id": "12.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The license is activated for the first time."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The license is placed on inactive status."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The license is suspended."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The license is canceled due to failure to complete continuing education."}]}, {"id": "12.14", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "5 days."}, {"label": "b", "text": "10 days."}, {"label": "c", "text": "30 days."}, {"label": "d", "text": "45 days."}]}, {"id": "12.15", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Affiliated licensees\u2019 licenses become inactive."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Affiliated licensees\u2019 licenses are immediately revoked."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Affiliated licensees\u2019 licenses are immediately transferred to another broker."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Affiliated licensees\u2019 licenses are not affected."}]}, {"id": "12.16", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "submit proof of errors and omissions insurance coverage."}, {"label": "b", "text": "enroll in a post-licensing course."}, {"label": "c", "text": "send the national criminal history report to the principal broker."}, {"label": "d", "text": "create an online services portal account."}]}, {"id": "12.17", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "commission rate."}, {"label": "b", "text": "advertising campaigns."}, {"label": "c", "text": "residential address."}, {"label": "d", "text": "marital status."}]}, {"id": "12.18", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "10"}, {"label": "b", "text": "15"}, {"label": "c", "text": "30"}, {"label": "d", "text": "48"}]}, {"id": "12.19", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "notify all affiliated licensees in the company."}, {"label": "b", "text": "return the sales associate\u2019s license to the Commission within 5 business days."}, {"label": "c", "text": "return the sales associate\u2019s license to the licensee."}, {"label": "d", "text": "ensure the sales associate finds another broker to affiliate with."}]}, {"id": "12.20", "question": "license is", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "suspended."}, {"label": "b", "text": "resigned."}, {"label": "c", "text": "revoked."}, {"label": "d", "text": "canceled."}]}, {"id": "12.21", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Sales associate applicants only"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Broker applicants only"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Reciprocal license applicants only"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Sales associate, broker, and reciprocal license applicants"}]}, {"id": "12.22", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Annually"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Every 2 years"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Every 3 years"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Every 4 years"}]}, {"id": "12.23", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It is required for all active licensees."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Licensees must obtain coverage through the Commission\u2019s group E&O policy."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Only brokers are required to maintain E&O insurance."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It is optional for all licensees."}]}, {"id": "12.24", "question": "least", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "$50,000 for one claim"}, {"label": "b", "text": "$75,000 for one claim"}, {"label": "c", "text": "$100,000 for one claim"}, {"label": "d", "text": "$250,000 for one claim"}]}, {"id": "12.25", "question": "within the previous", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "4 years."}, {"label": "b", "text": "6 years."}, {"label": "c", "text": "8 years."}, {"label": "d", "text": "10 years.\n\n\n\nState Test 13: Kentucky Brokerage Activities"}]}, {"id": "13.1", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A sales associate or broker who manages a main or branch office for a principal broker"}, {"label": "b", "text": "A broker who manages the main or branch office for several principal brokers"}, {"label": "c", "text": "A nonresident licensee who manages a branch office that is located within 100 miles of the main\noffice"}, {"label": "d", "text": "A licensee who operates a brokerage at more than one location"}]}, {"id": "13.2", "question": "Broker Sue receive a buyer\u2019s earnest money deposit on Tuesday morning. When is her deadline for\ndepositing this check into an escrow account?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Wednesday morning"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Wednesday night"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Thursday night"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Friday night"}]}, {"id": "13.3", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "A blog highlighting the services a licensee provides to clients"}, {"label": "b", "text": "A billboard message to the general public"}, {"label": "c", "text": "A phone message to a client"}, {"label": "d", "text": "An email blast to prospective clients"}]}, {"id": "13.4", "question": "with a seller whose property is listed with Delta Realty. Brenda will receive her commission from", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the buyer."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the seller."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the principal broker of Hometown Realty."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the principal broker of Delta Realty."}]}, {"id": "13.5", "question": "affiliated?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "When the property owner consents"}, {"label": "b", "text": "With written consent from the principal broker who listed the property"}, {"label": "c", "text": "When his or her principal broker and the other principal broker both give written consent"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Never"}]}, {"id": "13.6", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "identify the name of the principal broker or brokerage."}, {"label": "b", "text": "identify a specific property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "refrain from using the sales associate\u2019s name."}, {"label": "d", "text": "avoid subjective, understated descriptions."}]}, {"id": "13.7", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Including the broker\u2019s business identification on an advertisement"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Receiving an 8% commission on a property sale when the going rate is 6%"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Placing an excess number of signs on a property for sale"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Buying a property and disclosing their license status after the closing"}]}, {"id": "13.8", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Telemarketing calls are illegal after 5:00 p.m."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Telemarketers may never call telephone numbers on the National Do Not Call Registry."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Recipients of unwanted telemarketing calls may file a complaint with the Federal Trade\nCommission."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Telemarketers must discontinue a call within the first 5 minutes if the consumer indicates he or\nshe does not want to listen to a sales presentation."}]}, {"id": "13.9", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Answer questions about purchase agreements"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Negotiate prices"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Discuss home inspection results with clients"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Create brochures for open houses"}]}, {"id": "13.10", "question": "establishment of the office.", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "4"}, {"label": "b", "text": "5"}, {"label": "c", "text": "8"}, {"label": "d", "text": "10"}]}, {"id": "13.11", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "will not be subject to disciplinary action if he or she is being supervised by a principal broker."}, {"label": "b", "text": "will be prohibited from applying for a real estate license for 5 years."}, {"label": "c", "text": "has committed a felony and may be subject to incarceration."}, {"label": "d", "text": "may have to pay a fine as well as the amount of commission received from the unlicensed\nactivity."}]}, {"id": "13.12", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "If the principal broker knew about a violation and did not prevent it"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Only when the violation results in payment from the Education, Research, and Recovery Fund"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Only when the principal broker is also named in a written complaint"}, {"label": "d", "text": "When an unlawful act has caused more than $5000 in damages to a client"}]}, {"id": "13.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Licensees have 2 days to correct information in an online ad that is no longer true."}, {"label": "b", "text": "All internet and social media advertising must be approved first by the Commission before it can\nbe used."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Every individual viewable page of an Internet or social media ad is considered a separate\nadvertisement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "There are no specific rules that apply to Internet or social media advertising in Kentucky."}]}, {"id": "13.14", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the name must end with \u201cteam\u201d or group.\u201d"}, {"label": "b", "text": "other teams or groups within the brokerage may also use the same name."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the team or group may not use the assumed or alternate name in any advertising."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the name must be renewed with the Commission every six months."}]}, {"id": "13.15", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Sales associate who created the advertising"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Principal broker"}, {"label": "c", "text": "The person designated by the Kentucky Real Estate Commission to review advertising"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Associate brokers or sales associates acting as a designated manager"}]}, {"id": "13.16", "question": "documents", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "within 5 business days of signing."}, {"label": "b", "text": "within 24 hours of signing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "at signing."}, {"label": "d", "text": "only when the signer requests the copies."}]}, {"id": "13.17", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "for 3 years."}, {"label": "b", "text": "until the transaction closes."}, {"label": "c", "text": "until disbursement disputes are resolved."}, {"label": "d", "text": "for 5 years."}]}, {"id": "13.18", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Unaccepted offers"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Advertising proposals"}, {"label": "c", "text": "IRS personal income tax returns"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Phone bills"}]}, {"id": "13.19", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "logos."}, {"label": "b", "text": "brands."}, {"label": "c", "text": "open house signs that give directions only."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Internet ads."}]}, {"id": "13.20", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "only if the client has entered into a written agreement to compensate the broker for brokerage\nservices."}, {"label": "b", "text": "no later than 30 days before a listing agreement expires."}, {"label": "c", "text": "only when there is a net listing agreement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "regardless of whether the broker was able to produce a willing and able buyer for a seller\u2019s\nproperty."}]}, {"id": "13.21", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "whether a fee is charged for participating."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the penalty for failing to sell a property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "that a property must be sold within 30 days of signing the agreement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "that the brokerage firm sets the purchase price for the property."}]}, {"id": "13.22", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "must be interest bearing."}, {"label": "b", "text": "may be used for both business and third-party funds."}, {"label": "c", "text": "may not commingle the broker\u2019s funds with third-party funds."}, {"label": "d", "text": "may not be used to pay bank service fees."}]}, {"id": "13.23", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "2"}, {"label": "b", "text": "3"}, {"label": "c", "text": "4"}, {"label": "d", "text": "5"}]}, {"id": "13.24", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "It must be registered with the sales associate\u2019s principal broker."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It must be registered with the Commission."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It must include a nickname."}, {"label": "d", "text": "It must be recorded by the sales associate\u2019s principal broker."}]}, {"id": "13.25", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "establish penalties for cybersecurity breaches."}, {"label": "b", "text": "be updated at least every six months."}, {"label": "c", "text": "prohibit the disclosure of clients\u2019 confidential information by anyone affiliated with the firm."}, {"label": "d", "text": "be audited by a cybersecurity professional to ensure it meets state requirements."}]}, {"id": "13.26", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Retaining escrow fund records for the required two years"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Acting as an undisclosed dual agent"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Failing to recommend that a buyer obtain an inspection of a property"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Advertising listings without an advertising license"}]}, {"id": "13.27", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "License suspension"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Fines"}, {"label": "c", "text": "License revocation"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Incarceration"}]}, {"id": "13.28", "question": "broker\u2019s main office.", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "100"}, {"label": "b", "text": "125"}, {"label": "c", "text": "150"}, {"label": "d", "text": "200"}]}, {"id": "13.29", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "they work with a Kentucky cooperating broker."}, {"label": "b", "text": "they obtain prior approval from the Commission and their home state\u2019s Commission."}, {"label": "c", "text": "they work with another out-of-state broker."}, {"label": "d", "text": "they obtain a special reciprocal license for six months."}]}, {"id": "13.30", "question": "unlicensed brokerage activities. Which of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "James must wait 5 years before reapplying for another license."}, {"label": "b", "text": "James must pay a $1000 penalty for failing to timely renew."}, {"label": "c", "text": "James may not face disciplinary action if he reactivates his license within 1 year of its lapse."}, {"label": "d", "text": "James will have his license suspended."}]}, {"id": "13.31", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "mortgage holders"}, {"label": "b", "text": "licensed brokers"}, {"label": "c", "text": "property owners"}, {"label": "d", "text": "independent contractors"}]}, {"id": "13.32", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nsubmit an application, fee, and consent to service or process form for licensure in Kentucky.\ncomplete a state and FBI criminal records check prior to Kentucky licensure.\nmaintain an active place of business in Kentucky.\nwork with a Kentucky cooperating broker and list the broker\u2019s name in all advertising.", "answers": []}, {"id": "13.33", "question": "the principal broker?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The principal broker must appoint a team leader."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The principal broker must choose the team name."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The principal broker must notify the Commission about the team\u2019s alternate or assumed name."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The principal broker must create policies for the team\u2019s advertising."}]}, {"id": "13.34", "question": "prior business relationship. Beth\u2019s telephone number is registered on the Do Not Call Registry.\nWhich of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Beth may file a complaint with the Federal Trade Commission."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Beth may sue the broker in federal court."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Beth may request injunctive relief from a court."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Beth may request that the Commission impose punitive damages against the broker."}]}, {"id": "13.35", "question": "following is NOT such a requirement?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Escrow accounts must be registered with the Commission."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Brokers must deposit funds in interest-bearing escrow accounts."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Brokers may pay bank service fees out of escrow accounts."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Escrow accounts must be separate from personal or other business accounts."}]}, {"id": "13.36", "question": "be included in every ad it creates?\n.", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "name and license numbers of all affiliated licensees"}, {"label": "b", "text": "name of all team members"}, {"label": "c", "text": "name of all sales associates affiliated with the brokerage and the principal broker"}, {"label": "d", "text": "name of the principal broker or the brokerage"}]}, {"id": "13.37", "question": "pay for the repairs, Delia withdraws $500 of the buyer\u2019s earnest money deposit from the escrow\naccount without informing either party. Which statement is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Delia can withdraw escrow funds for this purpose if her principal broker consents."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Delia can withdraw escrow funds for this purpose if she repays the funds within 24 hours."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Delia can withdraw escrow funds for this purpose if the seller consents."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Delia cannot lawfully withdraw escrow funds for this purpose."}]}, {"id": "13.38", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "When they are in the process of applying to become a sales associate"}, {"label": "b", "text": "When they work for a brokerage firm in the state"}, {"label": "c", "text": "When they work under the supervision of a principal broker"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Unlicensed individuals may not engage in activities requiring licensing."}]}, {"id": "13.39", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Closing sheets"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Seller\u2019s Disclosure of Property Condition forms"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Earnest money receipts"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Team text messages"}]}, {"id": "13.40", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "at the time of signing"}, {"label": "b", "text": "no later than 1 business day after signing"}, {"label": "c", "text": "no later than 5 business days after signing"}, {"label": "d", "text": "no later than at closing\n\n\n\nState Test 14: License Law Requirements for Kentucky\nContracts"}]}, {"id": "14.1", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "give all oral offers to the client."}, {"label": "b", "text": "give all written offers to the client."}, {"label": "c", "text": "give only those written offers to the client that the broker knows contain acceptable terms."}, {"label": "d", "text": "give all oral and written offers to the client."}]}, {"id": "14.2", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "If at least two witnesses are present at its creation"}, {"label": "b", "text": "When used for commercial properties only"}, {"label": "c", "text": "If the lease is for a period less than one year"}, {"label": "d", "text": "If the lease is for a period more than two years"}]}, {"id": "14.3", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Within 2 days of receiving the offer"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Within 5 days of receiving the offer"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Only when requested by the seller"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Without delay"}]}, {"id": "14.4", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the proposed payment terms."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the name of the attorney representing the buyer."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the signature of the sellers only."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the name and address of the lender."}]}, {"id": "14.5", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the amount of the buyer\u2019s earnest money deposit."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the date and time the counteroffer expires."}, {"label": "c", "text": "a legal description of the property."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the maximum purchase price."}]}, {"id": "14.6", "question": "agreement has expired?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The seller initiates contact with the licensee and the new listing contract will not take effect until\nthe current listing contract expires."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The licensee agrees to a reduced commission for the new listing agreement."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The licensee signs a nondisclosure agreement."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Never."}]}, {"id": "14.7", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "the expiration date."}, {"label": "b", "text": "the name of the principal broker and brokerage company."}, {"label": "c", "text": "the listing price."}, {"label": "d", "text": "the name of the seller\u2019s attorney."}]}, {"id": "14.8", "question": "presented the buyer\u2019s purchase offer to the seller?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "directly to the buyer"}, {"label": "b", "text": "directly to the seller"}, {"label": "c", "text": "to the licensee representing the buyer"}, {"label": "d", "text": "to the principal broker representing the buyer and the principal broker representing the seller"}]}, {"id": "14.9", "question": "the market for quite some time. The house is currently listed with a competing brokerage. When can\nMaya negotiate a listing contract with the seller?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "after the house has been on the market for 1 year."}, {"label": "b", "text": "only if the seller initiates contact with Maya to discuss listing the house."}, {"label": "c", "text": "after Maya persuades the seller to terminate the existing listing contract."}, {"label": "d", "text": "no more than 30 days before the current listing contract is set to expire."}]}, {"id": "14.10", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The principal broker must deliver all written offers to the client without delay."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The principal broker must accept earnest money deposits."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The principal broker must help the client develop, negotiate, and present offers and counteroffers\nuntil the transaction is completed."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The principal broker owes all these duties to a seller client."}]}, {"id": "14.11", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "They are legally binding."}, {"label": "b", "text": "They may be used in residential transactions, but wet signatures are still preferred."}, {"label": "c", "text": "They may be used in Kentucky only for commercial transactions."}, {"label": "d", "text": "They may or may not be legally binding, depending on a locality\u2019s rules."}]}, {"id": "14.12", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Statute of limitations"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Statute of frauds"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Uniform Common Code"}, {"label": "d", "text": "NAR rules and regulations\n\n\n\nState Test 15: Disclosures and Agency Issues"}]}, {"id": "15.1", "question": "expected. Which of the following is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The licensee is barred from personally selling the property, since he is licensed."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The sales associate may sell the property provided he discloses the losses as shown on his income\ntax return."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The licensee may sell the property without restriction, regardless of the profitability."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The sales associate may sell the property provided he makes proper disclosures as to his license\nstatus."}]}, {"id": "15.2", "question": "A licensee shows a property to an interested buyer. During the second showing, the seller reveals\nthat the house was previously occupied by a person who died of AIDS. The buyer blames his agent\nfor not disclosing this fact and threatens to file a complaint with the Commission. Which of the\nfollowing is true?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The broker has failed to deal honestly and competently with the buyer prospect."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The broker has violated a duty to disclose unnatural deaths which have occurred in a listed\nproperty."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The broker has jeopardized the client\u2019s interests and could face disciplinary action."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The broker is not required to make any disclosures regarding AIDS."}]}, {"id": "15.3", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\na new home being purchased when a warranty is offered.\nproperty being sold at auction.\nproperty being sold due to a divorce.\nproperty being sold at a court-supervised foreclosure sale.", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.4", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nWhen the transaction closes\nIf the transaction does not close\nFive years after closing\nIt continues after the agency relationship ends.", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.5", "question": "different from a non-licensee selling the lot?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The licensee must provide current market value documentation."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The licensee may not list the property with her broker."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The licensee must tell the buyers that she is licensed as soon as they meet."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The licensee must disclose her license status in writing before signing any contract."}]}, {"id": "15.6", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nIt explains the fiduciary duties of obedience, loyalty, and accounting.\nIt educates consumers about the brokerage relationships available in Kentucky.\nIt establishes a written agency relationship between the principal broker and client.\nIt explains the remedies available if the relationship ends.", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.7", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nSeller\nSeller\u2019s agent\nSeller\u2019s agent and buyer\u2019s agent\nSeller and buyer", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.8", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nA broker properly maintains the firm\u2019s escrow account records.\nA closing agent ensures the settlement statement is accurate.\nA brokerage firm correctly calculates a licensee\u2019s commission split.\nA licensee ensures that all client money and property is handled properly.", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.9", "question": "Seller\u2019s Certificate.\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.10", "question": "habitable. Which of the following is true if he plans to sell the property?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nHe must notify the local health department.\nHe must give prospective buyers written notice disclosing the contamination.\nHe must disclose this information to prospective buyers only if they specifically ask.\nHe is not required to make any disclosures about the methamphetamine lab to prospective\nbuyers.", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.11", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nBefore signing a written agreement to provide brokerage services\nWithin 5 days after accepting an earnest money deposit\nWithin 10 days after discussing brokerage services\nAny time before closing", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.12", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nWhen a licensee is purchasing a condo unit from a former neighbor\nWhen a condo unit is being transferred as a gift\nWhen a court has ordered the sale of a condo unit\nWhen a condo unit is in foreclosure", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.13", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "one licensee represents the buyer while another licensee represents the seller."}, {"label": "b", "text": "one licensee represents both the buyer and the seller in the same transaction."}, {"label": "c", "text": "licensees from two different brokerages represent the buyer and the seller."}, {"label": "d", "text": "one licensee represents another licensee\u2019s client."}]}, {"id": "15.14", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The guide provides information on the real estate brokerage relationships available in Kentucky."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Licensees may give prospective clients the guide at any point in the relationship but no later than\nclosing."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The guide is mandatory for commercial real estate transactions."}, {"label": "d", "text": "A real estate transaction may be voided by a consumer who does not receive a guide."}]}, {"id": "15.15", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "must document attempts to deliver the guide."}, {"label": "b", "text": "must not deliver or present any offer for the subject property."}, {"label": "c", "text": "must cancel the existing agency relationship."}, {"label": "d", "text": "may refuse to list the seller\u2019s property."}]}, {"id": "15.16", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\ninformation on cooperation between brokerage firms.\ninformation on real estate teams.\ninformation on fair housing.\ninformation on environmental hazards.", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.17", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nLoyalty\nCompensation\nConfidentiality\nReasonable care and diligence", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.18", "question": "the seller\u2019s agent deliver the Seller\u2019s Disclosure of Property Condition document to the buyer?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nWithin 24 hours\nWithin 48 hours\nWithin 72 hours\nWithin 96 hours", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.19", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nresidential property being sold when there are multiple offers.\nnew residential property sold with a warranty.\nproperty sold at a court-supervised foreclosure sale.\nproperty sold at auction.", "answers": []}, {"id": "15.20", "question": "Gary to represent the buyer in a transaction involving one of the firm\u2019s listings. In this transaction,\nJudy and Gary are considered\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\ndual agents.\ndesignated agents.\nundisclosed dual agents.\nsingle agents.\n\n\n\nState Test 16: Property Management and Other Kentucky Laws", "answers": []}, {"id": "16.1", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Information about the principal broker\u2019s record management system"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Property owner\u2019s name and address"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Effective dates of the agreement and whether the property owner agrees to automatic annual\nrenewal"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Amount or method of computing the principal broker\u2019s compensation"}]}, {"id": "16.2", "question": "transactions related to the property?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nBy December 1 every year\nAt least quarterly\nAt least semi-annually\nMonthly by the date stated in the property management agreement", "answers": []}, {"id": "16.3", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.", "answers": []}, {"id": "16.4", "question": "", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "Security deposits may be kept in a principal broker\u2019s personal account."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Tenants must be given a list of any existing damage to the unit and estimated cost to repair\nbefore paying a security deposit."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Tenants cannot pay more than 3 months\u2019 rent as a security deposit."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Landlords may keep security deposits only if a tenant fails to pay the last month\u2019s rent."}]}, {"id": "16.5", "question": "business days must he deposit the funds in an escrow account?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.", "answers": []}, {"id": "16.6", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nleases\nmonthly owner statements and reports\nowner and unit ledgers\nleases, monthly owner statements and reports, and owner and unit ledgers", "answers": []}, {"id": "16.7", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nFamilial status\nMilitary status\nNational origin\nDisability", "answers": []}, {"id": "16.8", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe replacement value of property.\nthe assessed value of property.\nthe millage value of property.\nthe broker's estimate of value.", "answers": []}, {"id": "16.9", "question": "a.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nTitle officer\nBuyer\nLender\nSeller\n\n\n\nSection VI: Kentucky License\nExamination Sample Test\nSample Test: Kentucky Practice Exam\nS 1.\n\nA farmer temporarily installs produce coolers in a leased farm stand in order to prevent spoilage.\nThe coolers would be considered which of the following?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nS 2.\n\nProperty can be converted from real to personal property and from personal property to real property\nby means of which processes, respectively?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nS 3.\n\nit can be passed on to heirs.\nit has no restrictions on use.\nthe estate may revert to a grantor or heirs if the prescribed use changes.\nit is of unlimited duration.\n\nMaria acquires a property from her uncle Alfonso. When Maria dies, the estate will pass to\nAlfonso's other niece, Serena. The type of estate that Maria has in the property is a\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nS 6.\n\nlegal life estate.\nconventional life estate.\ndefeasible fee simple estate.\nabsolute fee simple estate.\n\nThe distinguishing feature of a defeasible fee simple estate is that\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nS 5.\n\nAssemblage and plottage.\nApplication and dissolution.\nSeverance and affixing.\nPlanting and harvesting.\n\nThe highest form of ownership interest one can acquire in real estate is the\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nS 4.\n\nTrade fixtures that are real property.\nTrade fixtures that are personal property.\nTemporary real property.\nEmblements.\n\nconventional life estate.\nlegal life estate.\nfee simple defeasible estate.\ntenancy by the entireties.\n\nOne difference between a cooperative estate and a condominium estate is that\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\na condominium owner owns a unit of air space whereas the co-op owner owns a proprietary\nlease.\na condominium sale adversely affects other unit owners.\nthe coop owner owns stock and a freehold real estate interest whereas the condominium owner\nsimply a proprietary lease.\nthe condominium owner owns the common elements and the airspace whereas the coop owner\nonly owns the apartment.\n\n\n\nS 7.\n\nWho are the essential parties involved in an estate in trust?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nS 8.\n\nA condominium owner enjoys a\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nS 9.\n\nOwner, trustor and lawyer.\nOwner, trustor and trustee.\nTrustee, title company, and beneficiary.\nTrustor, trustee and beneficiary.\n\nshare in an association that owns one's apartment.\ntenancy in common interest in airspace and common areas of the property.\nfee simple ownership of the airspace in a unit and an undivided share of the entire property's\ncommon areas.\nfee simple ownership of a pro rata share of the entire property.\n\nWith various types of junior liens, the order of payment priority is generally established according to\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe date of recordation.\nwhat form of tax is in question.\nthe order of disbursement.\nwhether the lien was subordinated.\n\nS 10. What is a lien-theory state in contrast to a title-theory state?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nA state in which liens are given priority over other encumbrances.\nA state in which a mortgagor retains title to the property when a mortgage lien is created.\nA state in which the holder of a mortgage lien receives title to the mortgaged property until the\ndebt is satisfied.\nA state in which liens must be recorded to be enforceable.\n\nS 11. A property owner has an easement appurtenant on her property. One day the property is sold to\nanother party who is opposed to the easement. Following the closing, this particular form of\neasement\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nterminates.\ntransfers with the property.\ntransfers with the owner to a new property.\nbecomes a license on the property.\n\nS 12. What fundamental legal purpose is fulfilled by title records?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nKeeping the county apprised of tax payments.\nPreventing identity theft.\nGiving constructive notice of one's rights and interests in the property.\nAssembling all relevant documents in a single place.\n\nS 13. What is \"chain of title?\"\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThe list of all parties who have ever owned real estate.\nThe bundle of rights linked to the recorded title to a parcel.\nA chronology of successive owners of record of a parcel of real estate.\nInvoluntary conveyance of title by statutory rules of descent.\n\nS 14. Which of the following provides the strongest evidence of marketable title?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nA general warranty deed.\nA title certificate.\nTitle insurance.\nAn attorney's opinion.\n\n\n\nS 15. A store owner enters into a lease that charges rent per square foot, a common area fee, and a portion\nof the store owner's gross income from the property. This kind of lease is a\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\ntriple charge, or triple net lease.\nproprietor's lease.\npercentage lease.\nretailer's gross lease.\n\nS 16. An owner leases a property to a business in exchange for rent. The tenant is required to pay all\noperating expenses as well. This is an example of a\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nproprietary lease.\npercentage lease.\ngross lease.\nnet lease.\n\nS 17. A lease automatically terminates under which of the following circumstances?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThe tenant fails to pay rent.\nThe leased property is foreclosed.\nThe tenant goes out of business.\nThe landlord cancels the lease.\n\nS 18. A county or municipal authority usually grants a certificate of occupancy for new construction only\nafter\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nall contractors\u2019 work has been inspected.\nall work has been completed for at least sixty days.\nthe construction conforms to building codes.\nthe tax assessor has valued the improvement.\n\nS 19. A property owner is precluded by deed restriction from developing a thirty foot boat dock. The\nlimitation prompts the owner to sell to another party. The new owner\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nis free to build the dock since the next door neighbor built a similar dock two weeks later.\ntakes title subject to the same restriction.\ncan build the dock with special permission from the zoning board.\nmay build, since the restriction is extinguished by the sale.\n\nS 20. Emily sells Rycole a property containing a deed condition. The condition stipulates that the forested\nportion of the property must never be razed for development. Three months later, Rycole proceeds\nto harvest the trees and turn the area into an executive golf course. What recourse, if any, does\nEmily have under the deed condition?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nShe has the right to re-possess the property because the grantee has violated the condition.\nThe condition has ceased to apply because she allowed the violation to continue for a certain\nperiod of time.\nShe can claim the proceeds from the harvested trees.\nShe can force Rycole to sell the property to a new owner who agrees to comply with the\ncondition.\n\nS 21. What is the essential purpose of legal descriptions of real property?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nTo create a consistent, unchanging standard for uniquely locating a property.\nTo enable courts and attorneys to calculate property size accurately.\nTo comply with common law for real property.\nTo eliminate cumbersome metes and bounds descriptions.\n\n\n\nS 22. Which of the following characterizes metes and bounds descriptions?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThey use meridians and base lines.\nThey identify an enclosed area, beginning and ending at the same point.\nThey use lot and block numbers.\nThey incorporate elevation into the descriptions.\n\nS 23. A buyer agrees to all terms of a seller's offer except the length of time for a contingency to procure\nfinancing. The buyer extends the financing period in the offer by one week, signs the form, and\nmails it back to the seller. At this point, the seller's offer\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nis void.\nbecomes an executory contract.\nbecomes a counteroffer.\nhas been accepted, since the modification was a contingency.\n\nS 24. Real estate contracts that are not personal service contracts\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nmay be assigned.\nare not assignable.\nmust be in writing.\nare exempt from the statute of frauds.\n\nS 25. Which of the following contracts must be in writing to be enforceable?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nA parol contract.\nA six-month lease.\nA two-year lease.\nAn executory contract.\n\nS 26. Agent Bob, who works for Broker Bill, obtains an owner listing to lease a building. Bill's other\nagent, Sue, locates a tenant for Bob's listing. Broker Bill in this instance is\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nan implied agent.\na dual agent.\na single agent.\na subagent.\n\nS 27. A transaction broker should disclose his or her agency relationship to prospective buyers and sellers\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nupon first substantive communication.\nupon completion of the listing agreement.\nimmediately following completion of any offer.\nimmediately prior to closing.\n\nS 28. A transaction facilitator in a residential transaction represents\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe seller.\nthe buyer.\nboth seller and buyer.\nneither seller nor buyer.\n\nS 29. A principal instructs an agent to inform minority buyers that the property for lease was just leased an\nhour ago and is no longer available. The agent refuses to comply. In this case,\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe agent should exercise caution until the listing expires, then decline to renew it.\nthe principal has proposed an illegal act, which should not be obeyed.\nthe agent is liable for breaching the listing terms.\nthe agent may sue the principal for discrimination and misrepresentation.\n\n\n\nS 30. The amount of a real estate broker's commission is established by\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nagreement among competing brokers.\nnegotiation with clients.\nthe local Board of Realtors\u00ae.\nstate real estate license law.\n\nS 31. A client revokes an exclusive right-to-sell listing two months prior to expiration. The reason stated:\nthe client is too busy to meet with the agent. In this case,\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe client is criminally liable for negligence.\nthe client may be liable for a commission and marketing expenses.\nthe agent can sue the client for specific performance, even if no customer had been located.\nthe agent must accept the revocation without the possibility of damage recovery.\n\nS 32. A protection period clause in an exclusive listing provides that\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe owner is protected from all liabilities arising from the agent's actions performed within the\nagent's scope of duties.\nthe agent has a claim to a commission if the owner sells or leases to a party within a certain time\nfollowing the listing's expiration.\nagents are entitled to extend a listing agreement's term if a transaction is imminent.\nan owner is not liable for a commission if a prospective customer delays in completing an\nacceptable offer.\n\nS 33. Real estate advertising must conform to regulatory standards and requirements. One requirement is\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\na broker may only place blind ads in social media outlets.\na broker must have all advertising approved by the local real estate board.\nthe advertising must not be deceptive.\nsales agents may only advertise in their own name.\n\nS 34. The three principal brokerage firms in a market agree to pay sales agents 15% more than any other\ncompetitor currently in practice. This is an example of\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\ncollusion.\nprice fixing.\nallocation of markets.\nsteering.\n\nS 35. Two leading agencies jointly agree to raise commissions charged to residential sellers to 7.5% of the\nsales price. Which of the following is true?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThis is a perfectly legitimate business practice.\nThe brokers have illegally fixed prices.\nThe brokers have allocated markets.\nThe brokers have engaged in legal collusion.\n\nS 36. A sale contract contains an open-ended financing contingency: if the buyer cannot obtain financing\nwithin a reasonable time, the deal is off. Six months later, the buyer still cannot secure financing.\nWhich of the following is true?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThe seller may cancel the contract, since it can be ruled invalid.\nThe buyer can continue indefinitely to seek financing, and the seller's property must remain off\nthe market, since \u201creasonable\u201d is not defined.\nThe escrow agent is entitled to the buyer's deposit.\nThe seller can force a lender to commit to a loan under fair financing laws.\n\n\n\nS 37. In the event of a buyer's default, a provision for liquidated damages in a sale contract enables a seller\nto\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nsue the buyer for specific performance.\nforce the buyer to quitclaim equitable title.\nsue the buyer for the broker's marketing expenses.\nclaim the deposit as compensated damages for the buyer's failure to perform.\n\nS 38. Which of the following is true of an option-to-buy agreement?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThe potential buyer, the optionee, is obligated to buy the property once the option agreement is\ncompleted.\nThe optionor must perform if the optionee takes the option, but the optionee is under no\nobligation to do so.\nThe contract can be executed at no cost to the optionee.\nIt is a bilateral agreement.\n\nS 39. If a manufacturer that is the major employer in a small city moves its operations to another city, it is\nreasonable to expect\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\na fall in housing demand, but no other changes in the real estate market.\na decline in demand for all types of real estate in the real estate market.\nan immediate fall in the demand for industrial real estate, but no other changes in the real estate\nmarket.\nan immediate decline in the prices for industrial and office real estate, but no impact on the\nresidential market.\n\nS 40. If a commercial real estate market is undersupplied, it is likely that\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nrental prices in that market will fall.\nrental prices in that market will rise.\nrental prices will remain stable until equilibrium is reached.\nconstruction will increase to the point of equilibrium.\n\nS 41. The amount of available property that becomes occupied over a period of time is called\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nvacancy.\nabsorption.\nequilibrium.\noccupation.\n\nS 42 The roof of a property cost $20,000. The economic life of the roof is 20 years. Assuming the\nstraight-line method of depreciation, what is the depreciated value of the roof after 3 years?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n$20,000.\n$17,000.\n$14,000.\n$3,000.\n\nS 43. The income capitalization approach to appraising value is most applicable for which of the following\nproperty types?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nSingle family homes.\nApartment buildings.\nUndeveloped land.\nChurches.\n\n\n\nS 44. In the income capitalization approach, an appraiser\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nestimates gross income and multiplies times the gross income multiplier.\nestimates effective income, subtracts tax, and applies a capitalization rate.\nestimates net income and applies a capitalization rate to it.\nestimates potential income and applies a capitalization rate to it.\n\nS 45. Net operating income is equal to\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\npotential income minus expenses minus debt service.\neffective gross income minus potential income.\npotential gross income minus vacancy and credit loss minus expenses.\neffective gross income minus vacancy and credit loss.\n\nS 46. If net income on a property is $40,000 and the cap rate is 10%, the value of the property using the\nincome capitalization method is\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n$100,000.\n$400,000.\n$1,000,000.\n$4,000,000.\n\nS 47. The key feature of an adjustable mortgage loan is that\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe interest rate may vary.\nthe monthly payment increases over the life of the loan.\nthe principal balance does not amortize.\nthe loan term can be shortened or lengthened.\n\nS 48. Why is a wraparound mortgage loan potentially interesting to a home seller as an investment?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nIt is a senior loan that can be easily subordinated for additional debt.\nA wraparound lender can profit when the interest rate of the wraparound exceeds that of the\nunderlying mortgage.\nThe underlying loan is retired early.\nThe second mortgage borrower may make payments directly to the first mortgage lender.\n\nS 49. A builder is required to secure a loan with mortgages on three properties. This is an example of\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\na participation mortgage loan.\na blanket mortgage loan.\na permanent mortgage loan.\na bridge loan.\n\nS 50. Which of the following is true of a loan with negative amortization?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThe interest rate on the loan increases as the principal balance decreases.\nPayments are not sufficient to retire the loan.\nThe loan balance is diminishing, or going negative.\nAdditional interest is being added to the monthly payment.\n\nS 51. The loan-to-value ratio is used as an underwriting mechanism because\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe LTV determines the profitability of the loan.\nthe loan amount needs to be less than the property's value.\nborrowers tend to inflate the true value of the property.\na full-price loan overfinances the borrower.\n\n\n\nS 52. In the past, borrowers were often surprised by unexpected or undisclosed borrowing fees and\nexpenses at closing. This phenomenon has been largely corrected through disclosure requirements\nmandated by which of the following laws?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nEqual Credit Opportunity Act\nTruth-in-Lending laws\nNational Disclosure Procedures Act\nFederal Fair Housing Laws\n\nS 53. Which of the following is an important function of the secondary mortgage market?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nParticipants borrow funds from banks so the banks can make more loans.\nParticipants issue tax certificates and sell them to primary lenders.\nParticipants purchase pools of defaulted loans from lenders to keep them solvent.\nParticipants sell mortgage-backed securities in order to buy pools of loans.\n\nS 54. Cash flow is a measure of how much pre-tax or after-tax cash an investment property generates. To\nderive cash flow it is therefore necessary to exclude\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\ncost recovery expense.\ninterest expense.\nloan principal payments.\nnet operating income.\n\nS 55. The method for deriving an investor\u2019s return on investment, or ROI, is by\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\ndividing net operating income by cash flow.\nmultiplying the required yield times after-tax cash flow.\ndividing net income by the price paid for the property.\nmultiplying cash flow times the price paid for the property.\n\nS 56. Which of the following items would affect a homeowner's adjusted basis?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nInstalling a higher capacity air conditioning and purifying system.\nReplacing a washing machine.\nStripping and staining hardwood floors.\nReplacing a broken picture window.\n\nS 57. Which of the following is true with respect to real property taxation by the federal government?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nIt imposes ad valorem property taxes and capital gain tax.\nIt may not impose property taxes or tax liens.\nThere are no federal ad valorem taxes on real property.\nIt imposes ad valorem tax, but not capital gain tax.\n\nS 58. Ad valorem taxes are based on\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe replacement value of property.\nthe assessed value of property.\nthe millage value of property.\nthe broker's estimate of value.\n\nS 59. A retirement facility prohibits ownership of any unit by persons under 55 years of age. The\nassociation claims it has made the prohibition properly. Which of the following is true?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThey are violating the Civil Rights Act of 1866.\nThey are violating the Fair Housing Amendments Act of 1988.\nThey are guilty of age discrimination.\nThe prohibition may be legal if performed correctly.\n\n\n\nS 60. An agent receives a full-price offer from a minority party. The agent presents the offer to the seller\nand discloses the buyer\u2019s minority status. The seller at that point instructs the agent to inform the\nbuyer that the property has just gone under contract. The agent duly complies, telling the offeror\nthat the home has just been temporarily removed from the market and is unavailable \u2013 but may be\navailable soon if the contract falls through. Which party or parties, if any, have violated fair\nhousing laws?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThe agent only.\nThe owner only.\nThe agent and the owner.\nNeither agent nor owner.\n\nS 61. Which of the following are examples of closing items not prorated between buyer and seller?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nTaxes.\nInspection fees.\nUtilities.\nCondominium assessments.\n\nS 62. Which of the following activities is not allowed under the Real Estate Settlements and Procedures\nAct?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nA broker having any business relationship with an insurance company that is involved in the\nbroker's transaction.\nA broker pre-qualifying a buyer for a mortgage loan.\nA lender requiring a deposit from a borrower for a tax and insurance escrow account.\nA lender paying a fee to a broker for referring a borrower to the lender.\n\nS 63. Which of the following communication records must (as opposed to should) be kept?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nNotes on every conversation.\nCopies of required communications to principals.\nNotes from company training sessions.\nBusiness cards of licensees one meets at open houses.\n\nS 64. To minimize the risk of violating fair housing laws, a licensee should\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nrefuse to use terms that refer to or describe any of the classes of persons protected by the laws.\navoid working in neighborhoods that are predominantly occupied by a single ethnic group.\nmake discriminatory or derogatory remarks in conversation only, never in writing.\ngive better service to members of a protected class than is standard for other clients or\ncustomers.\n\nS 65. What are \u201ctenant improvements?\u201d\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nModifications to a rental suite to conform to a tenant\u2019s usage specifications\nMarketing programs that yield a higher quality of tenant\nIncreased revenue resulting from a rise in rental rates\nIncreased occupancy resulting from a population increase in the market area\n\nS 66. For the proper handling of client and owner monies, a property manager is generally required to\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\ndeposit all funds every month in the management firm\u2019s central operating account.\nemploy a notary to witness and record every deposit or payment received.\nmaintain a special trust account in a qualified financial depository.\ndisburse all funds to their legal owners on a weekly basis.\n\n\n\nS 67. Jennifer advised her clients they needed to paint their living room before showing the property. The\nwalls of these rooms were all 8\u2019 high. The wall lengths were 14\u2019, 18\u2019, 16\u2019, and 18\u2019. If a gallon of\npaint covers 200 SF, how many whole gallons would the homesellers have to buy?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n\nS 68. An investor just purchased a rectangular 2-acre retail lot for $2,500 a frontage foot. If she paid\n$1,000,000 total, what was the depth of the lot?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n400\u2019\n250\u2019\n871\u2019\n218\u2019\n\nS 69. Andra can afford to spend $5,000 in closing costs to refinance her home. The lender quotes closing\ncosts of $800 plus 2 points. The house appraised out at $240,000, and she can get an 80% loan.\nCan Annika afford to refinance?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nNo, she is short by $64.\nNo, she is short by $1,600.\nYes, with $360 left over.\nYes, she in fact breaks even.\n\nS 70. A lender offers an investor a maximum 70% LTV loan on the appraised value of a property. If the\ninvestor pays $230,000 for the property, and this is 15% more than the appraised value, how much\nwill the investor have to pay as a down payment?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n$93,150\n$79,350\n$90,000\n$69,000\n\nS 71. A house is being appraised using the sales comparison approach. The house has three bedrooms,\ntwo bathrooms, and a patio. The appraiser selects a comparable house that has three bedrooms, 2.5\nbathrooms, and no patio. The comparable house just sold for $400,000. A half-bath is valued at\n$20,000, and a patio at $4,000. Assuming all else is equal, what is the adjusted value of the\ncomparable?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n$400,000\n$416,000\n$384,000\n$424,000\n\nS 72. A family purchased a $90,000 lot to build a custom home. At the date of closing, the lot was\nassessed at $84,550 and the tax rate was $1.91 / $100 assessed valuation. When they completed the\nhome, the assessment increased by $235,000 to include the new construction. If the monthly tax\nescrow is based on the assessed value, what will the monthly tax escrow be?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n$517\n$6096\n$508\n$367\n\n\n\nS 73. The James family purchased a home for $360,000 five years ago and obtained an 80% LTV loan.\nNow the property has appreciated 25%. In addition, the loan has been paid down $22,000. What is\nthe James\u2019s current equity in the home?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n$94,000\n$162,000\n$90,000\n$184,000\n\nS 74. George and Mary have owned a rental house for 10 years. They bought it for $240,000 and\nestimated the land value @ 25%. If the property is depreciated on a 39-year schedule, and\nappreciation totals 50% over the period, what is their gain if they sell the property today?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n$159,230\n$166,150\n$181,538\n$120,000\n\nS 75. Adelpha\u2019s home is valued at $250,000. She has insurance coverage of $160,000 with an 80% coinsurance clause. If Adelpha has a damage claim amounting to $100,000, how much will she\nreceive from her policy?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n$32,000\n$60,000\n$80,000\n$100,000\n\nS 76. The Kentucky Real Estate Commission consists of ________ members.\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n\nS 77. Which of the following is true regarding the Kentucky Education, Research, and Recovery Fund?", "answers": [{"label": "a", "text": "The fund may pay claimants up to $100,000 per claim."}, {"label": "b", "text": "The fund reimburses parties damaged by the improper actions of licensees."}, {"label": "c", "text": "The fund exists to assist licensees in financing the payment of judgments to consumers."}, {"label": "d", "text": "The fund exists to help license applicants pay application and licensing exam fees.\nS 78. By what date must licensees complete 6 hours of continuing education each year?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nDecember 1\nDecember 15\nDecember 31\nJanuary 1\n\nS 79. All of the following are exempt from real estate licensure except one. Which one is not exempt?"}, {"label": "a", "text": "A Kentucky attorney"}, {"label": "b", "text": "A party acting under the direction of a court"}, {"label": "c", "text": "A property manager who lives in an onsite rental unit"}, {"label": "d", "text": "A city worker who wants to list and sell her neighbor\u2019s home for compensation\n\n\n\nS 80. Jordan forgot to renew his broker license by the March 31 deadline of his renewal year. Which of the\nfollowing is true?"}, {"label": "a", "text": "Jordan may not engage in real estate brokerage activity until he reactivates his license."}, {"label": "b", "text": "Jordan has a 30-day grace period after his license is cancelled to continue practicing real estate."}, {"label": "c", "text": "Jordan must take extra continuing education to reactivate his license."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Jordan may complete any real estate transactions he was engaged in before his license was\ncancelled.\nS 81. Licensees who place their license on inactive status"}, {"label": "a", "text": "may engage in limited real estate brokerage activities while the license is inactive."}, {"label": "b", "text": "must pay the biennial renewal fees for each renewal period the license is inactive."}, {"label": "c", "text": "must obtain extended reporting period coverage insurance for 5 years."}, {"label": "d", "text": "must re-take the state sales associate licensing exam to reactivate the license\nS 82. An applicant for a broker license must have held a sales associate license\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nfor 1 year immediately preceding the application for broker licensure.\nfor 5 of the preceding 10 years.\nduring the prior 2 years, working at least 20 hours per week.\nduring the prior 3 years, working at least 40 hours per week.\n\nS 83. Which of the following is a license law violation?"}, {"label": "a", "text": "Placing numerous for sale signs on a property"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Advertising listings without an advertising license"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Failing to recommend that a buyer obtain a home inspection"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Licensees buying property without disclosing their licensee status\nS 84. A principal broker must maintain transaction records for what period of time?"}, {"label": "a", "text": "one year."}, {"label": "b", "text": "two years."}, {"label": "c", "text": "three years."}, {"label": "d", "text": "five years.\nS 85. Which of the following compensation scenarios would constitute a license law violation?"}, {"label": "a", "text": "Paying a licensed auctioneer when a licensee and auctioneer collaborate to sell real estate at\nauction"}, {"label": "b", "text": "Paying a referral fee to an out-of-state broker"}, {"label": "c", "text": "Splitting a commission with an unlicensed party who is performing licensed activities"}, {"label": "d", "text": "Sharing or splitting a commission with a principal broker\nS 86. From whom may a licensee collect compensation?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThe client who is in an agency relationship with the licensee\nThe buyer who has submitted an offer on a property listed by the licensee\nThe licensee\u2019s principal broker\nThe courts after taking legal action against a client for nonpayment of commission\n\nS 87. When may buyers\u2019 agents advertise their role in a sale after the closing?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nIf the advertisement clearly states they worked as a buyer\u2019s agent\nIf their principal broker gives written consent\nIf the listing broker gives written consent\nIf the advertisement includes both the listing broker\u2019s and buyer agent\u2019s names\n\n\n\nS 88. If confidential information about a client is inadvertently disclosed, who must the principal broker\nnotify about the information breach?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThe Commission\nThe client\u2019s attorney\nThe client\nThe local REALTOR\u00ae association, if the client is a member\n\nS 89. When may an affiliated licensee\u2019s name appear larger than the principal broker\u2019s name in an\nadvertisement?"}, {"label": "a", "text": "when the affiliated licensee is advertising online"}, {"label": "b", "text": "when the affiliated licensee sponsors a charitable event"}, {"label": "c", "text": "when the affiliated licensee begins a new newspaper advertising campaign"}, {"label": "d", "text": "when the principal broker gives his or her approval to use such advertising\nS 90. Which of the following statements is NOT true about teams?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThe principal broker must appoint a team leader.\nThe team\u2019s name must end with \u201cteam\u201d or \u201cgroup.\u201d\nThe principal broker must establish policies for the team.\nThe team\u2019s name must include a nickname.\n\nS 91. Which of the following is true about net listings in Kentucky?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nThey are the most commonly used listing agreement.\nThey are discouraged in Kentucky.\nThey allow the seller to find the buyer and not compensate the agent.\nThey are illegal in Kentucky.\n\nS 92. An offer to purchase would NOT include\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nname of the licensee who completed or directed completion of the offer\nearnest money deposit amount\nautomatic renewal clause\nproposed payment terms\n\nS 93. Which of the following is NOT required in a listing contract?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nListing price\nSpecial directions of the owner regarding showings\nExpiration date of the contract\nName of the buyer\u2019s lending institution\n\nS 94. A listing agent received a written offer from a buyer\u2019s agent in another brokerage firm. What action\nshould the listing agent take at this point?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nPresent the offer to the seller client without delay.\nEncourage the seller to wait for a better offer.\nNotify the buyer\u2019s agent regarding the timeframe when the offer will likely be delivered.\nPresent the offer to the seller client within 120 hours.\n\nS 95. Broker Todd\u2019s seller client refused to complete and sign a Seller\u2019s Disclosure of Property Condition\nform. What should Todd do to protect himself from potential liability?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nDocument his client\u2019s refusal to complete and sign the form.\nImmediately terminate the listing agreement.\nComplete and sign the disclosure form as best as he can.\nDisclose information he knows about the property to the buyer.\n\n\n\nS 96. Which party is a dual agent when a brokerage company practices designated agency?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nDesignated agent for the seller\nPrincipal broker\nDesignated agent for the buyer\nAll affiliated licensees of the brokerage\n\nS 97. Broker Daniel is planning to meet with the Smiths to discuss listing their home with his brokerage\nfirm. At what point should Daniel present and explain the Guide to Agency Relationships?\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nWithin 24 hours after the Smiths sign a listing agreement\nBefore meeting the Smiths in person\nBefore entering into a written listing agreement with the Smiths\nNo later than at the closing of the sale of their home\n\nS 98. Which of the following is true regarding the Seller\u2019s Disclosure of Property Condition document?"}, {"label": "a", "text": "It is to be completed and given to a buyer at the seller\u2019s option and discretion."}, {"label": "b", "text": "It must be given to prospective buyers within 72 hours after receiving a written and signed offer\nto purchase."}, {"label": "c", "text": "It must be completed by the seller\u2019s agent, with direction from the seller."}, {"label": "d", "text": "Failure to deliver the document results in contract nullification.\nS 99. A principal broker must deposit rent money he or she receives into an escrow account within ____\nbusiness days.\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\n\nS 100. A property management agreement is NOT required to contain\na.\nb.\nc.\nd.\n\nthe name and address of the property owner\nnumber of units being managed\nprocedures for evicting tenants\nprocedures for returning and retaining security deposits\n\n."}]}]